接下来将为您呈现上周伦敦袭击事件的内幕
We come to you now with revelations about last week's attack in London.
匿名消息源提供了这段视频
An anonymous source provided this video.
记录了"神秘客"昆汀·贝克死前的一刻
It shows Quentin Beck, aka.Mysterio, moments before his death.
注意  以下视频可能引起不适
A warning, you may find this video disturbing.
我尽力将元素众送回空间裂缝
I managed to send the Elemental back through the rift but
但我觉得我可能会死在桥上
I don't think I'm gonna make it out of this bridge alive.
不知为何蜘蛛侠袭击了我
Spider-Man attacked me for some reason.
他拥有一支配备斯塔克科技的武装无人机军团
He has an army of weaponized drones, Stark technology.
他说  只有他才配成为新一代的钢铁侠
He's saying he's the only one who's gonna be the new Iron Man, no one else.
是否确认执行无人机攻击指令
Are you sure you want to commence the drone attack?
可能造成大规模伤亡
There will be significant casualties.
确认  全部执行
Do it. Execute them all.
这段惊人的视频  于今天早些时候
This shocking video was released earlier today
发布在备受争议的新闻网站"号角日报网"上
on the controversial news website TheDailyBugle.net.
你们看看  观众朋友们  证据确凿
There you have it, folks, conclusive proof
蜘蛛侠残忍地杀害了神秘客
that Spider-Man was responsible for the brutal murder of Mysterio,
这位来自异空间的勇士  为了保护我们的星球
an interdimensional warrior who gave his life
献出了自己的生命  毫无疑问
to protect our planet, and who will no doubt
他将名垂青史  成为有史以来最伟大的超级英雄
go down in history as the greatest superhero of all time.
但这还没完  观众朋友们
But that's not all, folks.
真正的重头戏刚刚开始  大家注意了  可别吓坏了
Here's the real blockbuster. Brace yourselves, you might wanna sit down.
蜘蛛侠的真实...蜘蛛侠的真名是...
Spider-Man's real... Spider-Man's real name is...
蜘蛛侠的真名是彼得·帕克
Spider-Man's name is Peter Parker.
我勒个——
What the f---
没错  观众朋友们  彼得·帕克  一个17岁的高中混混
That's right, folks. Peter Parker, a seventeen year old high school delinquent,
-怀有狂热杀人倾向   -她认识他
-harboring a homicidal hunger,   -She knows him.
-你是蜘蛛侠女朋友吗   -其实他就是恶贯满盈的私警
-Are you Spider-Man's girlfriend?   -He's in fact the vile vigilante,
-蜘蛛侠   -呦  是他啊
-Spider-Man!   -Yo it's him!
-哇哦  噢  请别碰她   -你居然只是个小屁孩
-Whoa, whoa, whoa. Please don't touch her.   -You're just a kid?
-是你杀了神秘客吗   -你居然只是个小屁孩
-You murdered Mysterio?   -You're just a kid?
-你协助他杀了神秘客吗  来啊   小屁孩   -不  我...我没有
-You helped him murder Mysterio?  Come on, kid.   -No, I... I didn't...
-让我看看你的真面目   -噢  噢  噢
-Let me see your face.   -Whoa, whoa, whoa!
他打我  蜘蛛侠打人了
He hit me. Spider-Man hit me!
-他打我  蜘蛛侠打人了   -一直以来
-He hit me. Spider-Man hit me!   -All the time,
人们敬仰这个男孩  称他为英雄
people looked up to this boy and called him a hero.
而我愿称他为  大众的头号公敌
I'll tell you what I call him: Public Enemy Number One!
都跟你说了  我再也不想这样荡来荡去啦
Told you I never wanna do this ever again!
MJ  对不起  但是我啥都看不见啊  你的手挡住了我的...
MJ, I'm so sorry but I can't see anything with your hand in my...
对不起  对不起  好了  现在我们去哪
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. Okay, where are we gonna go?
头号公敌
-不知道  去你家   -不行  不能去我家
-I don't know. Your house.   -Oh, no! We can't go to my house.
-我爸会杀了你的   -什么
-My Dad will kill you!   -What?
你不是说过你爸很喜欢我吗
I thought you said your Dad really liked me?
今非昔比了
Yeah, well, not anymore.
-兄弟   -哥们
-Dude.   -Dude!
-天呐   -天呐呐呐
-完犊子了   -是啊啊
-Dude!   -Dude!
-嘿   -啊...抱歉
-Dude!   -What... I'm so sorry!
-你还好吗   -不太好
-Are you okay?   -No, not really.
哟  彼得
Yo, Peter!
我们该走了  我们该走了  快快快
We should go. We should go. Come on.
-但是你刚刚说你不想荡蛛丝...   -别废话  荡就完事了
-But you said you don't wanna swing...   -Swing me. You should just swing me. Yeah.
好的  我们可以走地铁通道
Okay. We can take the subway.
小心
Look out!
刚才那下比空中飞人更难顶  好了  没事了
That was so much worse. Okay. It's okay.
你还好吗   -还行  还行
-Are you okay?   -Yeah. Yeah Yeah.
快快快  好了  真的很抱歉啊
Come on, come on, come on. Okay. I'm so sorry.
我感觉好蠢啊  我居然没意识到你过得很痛苦
I just feel so dumb. I didn't realize you were miserable.
不  我们其实挺开心的  不是吗
No, it was really fun, alright?
这就是大家所说的放纵一下
You know, that's why they call it a fling!
-放纵过就完了   -感觉很有趣
-And we flung.   -It was fun.
我本来可以更有趣的  我会搞笑那套的
I could've been more fun. I can be fun.
-咱们有空再约哦   -那...什么时候再约呢
-We'll hang out again.   -Like... when do you think?
-我得去看看什么情况   -别别别  哈皮
-I should see what that is.   -No. No, no, no, no. Happy.
-我就是干安保这块的   -他总是这样从窗户来去自由...
-It's what I do.   -He's always coming and going...
-彼得   -没啥大事...
-Peter?   -It's not...
-彼得  噢天呐  彼得...   -噢不  噢不  我好慌啊啊啊
-Peter? Oh. God. Peter...   -Oh, no. Oh, no. I don't know what to do!
彼得...
Peter...
-哦  我...天啊   -我们啥都没看见
-Oh. I. Oh my God.   -We didn't see anything.
-我啥都没看见   -不是你想的那样  哈皮
-I didn't see anything.   -This isn't what it looks like, Happy.
-不不   -对不起...
-No no.   -I'm sorry...
-记得做好安全措施...   -不是  梅姨  不是你们想的那样
-Just practice safe...   -No, May, this is not what it looks like.
噢  嘿
Oh, hey!
-你就是MJ吧   -是啊  你好
-You must be MJ!   -Yeah, hey.
-很高兴见到你   -很高兴见到你
-Nice to meet you.   -So nice to meet you.
等等  你哭了吗
Wait, have you been crying?
我们分手了
We broke up.
-嘿  蜘蛛侠   -噢  呃...
-Hey, Spider-Man!   -Oh, uh...
谢谢  我不知道你们分手了
Thank you. I didn't know you guys broke up.
我以为你们是真爱  梅姨
I thought you were in love, May.
-咱们能去厨房聊聊这事嘛   -我不知道  我觉得也许我该走了...
-Can we talk about this in the kitchen?   -I don't know. I should probably leave, I think...
我一直觉得你俩是天作之合...
I thought you guys were such a handsome couple...
-你懂的  其实就是保持界限的问题...   -噢...
-You know, it's really about boundaries...   -Oh...
-我去开门   -噢  等等  上这来
-Let me answer the door.   -Oh, hang on. Let's go in here.
-门铃响了吗   -嘿  他真的是蜘蛛侠嘛
-Is that the door?   -Hey, is it true?
-我本来要走的  但是...  -现在不行
-I was goona go but...   -Not now!
为什么你...
Why are you so...
-...老是谈性色变呢  彼得   -听着  我真的得...
-...awkward about sex, Peter.  -Look, I'm really gonna...
这跟性没关系
This has nothing to do with sex.
我该走了  但是如果你想重新开始...
I should go but if you wanna go over it again...
我的意思是...那是什么声音
I mean, I'm... What's that sound?
-嘿  蜘蛛侠   -哦天哪
-Hey, Spider-Man!   -Oh, my God.
如果你愿意的话我其实很乐意再续前缘  我只是不想...
I mean, I'm happy to rehash it if you want to. I just don't...
咱们各自管好自己的事
You take care of your side, I'll take care of mine.
-嗯   -这手机怎么老响
-Yeah   -What is up with this phone?
你们能不能别再刷手机了
Can you get off your phones for five minutes,
我只是想和你们谈谈你们的恋情  好吗
I just wanna talk to you about your relationship, okay?
彼得
Peter?
怎么了
What?
-那是...    -是这里吗
-Is that...   -Is that here?
-哟  彼得·帕克   -彼得
-Yo Peter Parker!   -Peter!
我觉得这应该没什么大不了的
I mean maybe it's not such a big deal.
蜘蛛煞
Spider-Menace!
世界各地的政府开始着手调查
Governments around the world launched investigations
杀人犯蜘蛛侠
into the murderer known as Spider-Man,
也就是彼得·帕克
aka, Peter Parker,
蛛网战犯
aka, the web-headed war criminal,
他多年以来一直在恐吓纽约的守法公民
who for years has been terrorizing the decent citizens of New York.
现在  纽约乃至全世界都看清了他的真面目
Well now, this city and the world see him for what he truly is.
杀人犯
Murderer!
神秘客万岁
Mysterio forever!
上星期伦敦遭受毁灭性袭击的细节现已披露
New details from last week's devastating attack in London have emerged.
我台已转接至联合情报总部...
For more, we go now to Joint Intelligence Headquarters...
刚刚权威人士证实
Authorities just a short while ago confirmed,
伦敦袭击中使用的致命无人机
that the deadly drones used in the London attack,
是史塔克工业设计的
were designed by Stark Industries.
-联邦探员查案  快开门   -联邦探员  你待在这儿
-Federal agents! Open up!   -Federal agents? You stay here!
我们是灾害控制局的
Department of Damage Control.
我们有彼得·帕克的逮捕令
We have a warrant for the arrest of Peter Parker.
-你知道宪法第四修正案吧   -当然
-You know the fourth amendment?   -Sure.
-知道什么叫不合理搜查和扣押么   -快进去吧  快点
-Unreasonable search and seizure?   -Get in here, guys. Let's go.
-我没杀昆汀·贝克  是无人机干的   -无人机是你的
-I didn't kill Quentin Beck. The drones did.   -The drones that are yours.
不是...听着...
No... Well, look...
尼克·弗瑞当时一直都在  去问他  他都知道
Nick Fury was there the entire time. Just ask him and he can explain everything.
尼克·弗瑞去年一整年都不在地球
Nick Fury has been off-planet for the last year.
什么
What?
彼得
Peter!
MJ  那个...
MJ! Uhh...
不关他们的事啊  先生
They had nothing to do with it, sir!
没有律师就保持沉默
Don't say anything without a lawyer.
我需要律师
I want a lawyer.
琼斯-沃森女士...
Miss Jones-Watson...
琼斯就好了  沃森就免了
Jones. I don't go by Watson.
琼斯女士...
Miss Jones...
-您为什么需要律师呢  如果...   -如果我是清白的
-Why do you want a lawyer if...   -I have nothing to hide?
-没错  除非...   -除非我并不无辜
-Exactly. Unless...   -I'm actually guilty of something?
我非常清楚你的小把戏和我的权利
I'm very aware of your tactics and my rights.
请你回答我的问题
Just answer my questions.
我看过你的档案
I've seen your file.
你是个聪慧年轻  前程似锦的女性
You're a smart, young woman with a bright future ahead of her.
干嘛和自己过不去  冒险和彼得·帕克这种私警混在一起呢
Why would you risk it all by getting involved with a vigilante like Peter Parker?
非常抱歉让你等了这么久
So sorry to keep you waiting.
-可以给内德拿点零食吗  他等了很久了   -没问题
-Can we get Ned a snack, please? He's been waiting,   -Absolutely.
-好嘞   -兄弟  真是抱歉
-I got you.   -Dude, I'm so sorry about that.
我什么都不该跟你说
I'm not supposed to say anything to you.
对  内德  你什么都不用说
No, Ned. Not even a thing.
我只有一个问题...
I just have one question...
当MJ告诉你  彼得是蜘蛛侠的时候...
When MJ told you that Peter was Spider-Man...
-等会儿等会儿...   -咋了
-Whoa, whoa, whoa...   -What's up?
我比MJ知道得早  我是蜘蛛侠的幕后帮手
I knew way before MJ did. I was Spider-Man's guy in the chair.
哦  这个我了解
Oh, I know about those.
老弟  我这儿大半的人都是干幕后技术活的
Dude, half my guys are guys in the chair.
就是啊  你懂了吧
Exactly! You would know.
是我帮他找到秃鹫的
I literally helped him find the Vulture.
这个我不知道欸
I didn't know that.
我还帮过他黑进他的战服  算是帮他去了太空
And I helped him hack his suit once, and kinda helped him get to Space.
所以  在蜘蛛侠的非法私警活动中  你是他的主要同谋喽
So, in Spider-Man's illegal vigilantism, you were his main accomplice.
我想把我的话从记录上删掉可以吗
I would like to have my words stricken from the record.
无意冒犯
With all due respect,
我希望你能明白
and I mean that very insincerely,
除非你对我们有明确的指控
unless you have some real specific charges to throw at us,
要不然从法律上来讲  你无权把我们拘留在这里
legally, you can't hold us here.
你绝对应该找个律师
You should definitely lawyer up.
什么意思
Excuse me?
危害儿童罪是项严重的指控
Child endangerment is a nasty rap.
这个男孩被托付给你
The boy was entrusted to you,
作为他的法定监护人  你基本上算是他母亲
and as his legal guardian, essentially his mother,
你不仅放任他祸害自己  还鼓励这种行为
you not only allowed him to endanger himself, but you actually encouraged it.
这还不算违法吗
Who does that?
我现在就要见彼得
I wanna see Peter right now.
史塔克工业今日被卷入蜘蛛侠和神秘客的争端中
Stark Industries was caught in the web of the Spider-Man-Mysterio controversy today,
联邦调查员已对失踪的史塔克科技产品展开调查
when federal agents opened an investigation into missing Stark technology.
调查员需要了解具体有哪些产品丢失...
The agents wanna know exactly what was taken...
-至少他们用了张好看的照片   -以及是否...
-At least they used a good picture.   -and whether or not...
又出啥事了
What is happening?
那太好了  谢谢
That's great. Thank you.
彼得  我这有好消息
Well, I have some good news, Peter.
我相信对你的任何指控都不会成立
I don't believe any of the charges against you are gonna stick.
等等  真的吗
Wait, seriously?
-哦  我就知道   -太棒了
-Oh, I knew it.   -Nice.
我的天啊  默多克先生  太谢谢了  这真的...
Oh, my God, Mr. Murdock. Thank you. That's...
-谢谢你  马特   -太棒了
-Thank you, Matt.   -That's amazing.
-不谢   -简直完美
-You are welcome.   -Perfect.
-但是...霍根先生   -好的
-However... Mister Hogan?   -Okay.
-咋了   -联邦调查局正在积极调查失踪的那些设备
-Yes?   -The feds are actively investigating the missing technology.
我理解你对斯塔克先生和他的公司十分忠诚
I understand you're loyal to Mr. Stark and his legacy,
但如果你被牵扯在内的话...
but if you were involved...
-什么叫  如果我被牵扯在内   -我建议你请律师
-If I was involved?   -I might secure a lawyer.
我需要律师...呃...  因为我被调...  我以为他会...
I need a lawyer because I'm un... I'm under inves... I thought, he was...
你说不会有指控了  我可以这么说...
you said, there's no charge. I can say, un...
在律师的建议下  我拒绝回答这个问题
under advisement of counsel, I refuse to answer the question
无意冒犯  因为...我的回答可能会让我进监狱
respectfully because I... the answer could incriminate me.
《好家伙》里有句话  怎么说来着
It's in Goodfellas. What's the thing they say in Goodfellas?
*注：《好家伙》是马丁·斯科西斯执导的黑帮犯罪影片
我知道你想说什么...冷静下好吗
I know, that's what you think... Calm down.
让我们听听他怎么说  马特
Let's hear what he has to say. Matt?
你得请个好律师
You're gonna need a really good lawyer.
彼得  你可能躲过了法律上的麻烦  但事情还没完呢
Peter, you may have dodged your legal troubles, but things will get much worse.
舆论的箭更伤人
There is still the court of public opinion.
杀人犯  神秘客万岁
Murderer! Mysterio forever!
你怎么做到的
How did you just do that?
因为我是个好律师
I'm a really good lawyer.
我们相信神秘客
我们得找个更安全的住处
We're gonna need a safer place to live.
哦  这个
Oh. Ah.
我们怎么...关掉这个
How do we... how do we?
警报系统  已解除
Alarm systems, deactivated.
看上去不错  这里...
It looks nice and this is....
也挺安全
safe.
欢迎来到心灵绿洲
Welcome, to the spiritual oasis.
你喜欢小金刚吗
You like Donkey Kong Jr.?
来自新泽西的尼基  热线已为您接通
Nicky from Jersey City, you're on the line.
我不是说我不想纪念复仇者联盟哈
I'm not saying I don't want to honor the Avengers,
但是  不是以这种方式纪念啊
but, you know, not doing it this way.
把美国队长的盾牌放在自由女神像上
Putting the Captain America shield on the Statue of Liberty?
不行  那样看起来太荒唐了
Nah, that will look ridiculous.
别打自由女神像的主意
Leave the Statue of Liberty alone.
哦  哈皮
Oh, Happy.
你交申请了吗
Did you send in your applications yet?
我刚刚向麻省理工投了申请  你呢
I literally just finished my MIT one. You?
-我也   -想想看要是咱们都进了
-Same.   -Imagine if we both got in?
-还有内德   -对啊  但是...
-And Ned?   -Yeah, but...
我们必须拿到奖学金  才真的能去
We have to get scholarships so we could actually go.
得了吧  你成绩又好  绩点又高  而且...
Come on. You got the scores, and the grades, and...
-你觉得我太现实了   -呃  不不不  不是的
-You think I'm being too pragmatic.   -No, no, no, no. Well...
是有一点  但问题不大
Kind of. That's okay.
我最喜欢你的这个特点
That's one of my favorite things about you.
-真的吗   -对啊
-Really?   -Yeah.
哦  那你还喜欢我什么
Well, what are your other favorite things?
我就喜欢你是个无所畏惧的乐天派
I love your relentless optimism.
那倒是  我的确是个心态乐观的姑娘
Yeah. I am a "glass half full" kind of gal.
我很喜欢跟谁都玩得来的你
I really like how you're a people person.
我可喜欢跟人打交道了
I love people.
超级...喜欢
Love 'em... so much.
你还喜欢运动
You like sports.
我觉得纽约大都会队今年也会一路过关斩将的
I think the Mets are gonna go all the way this year.
-真的吗   -那是什么声音
-Really?   -What's that noise?
噢  那个是...是哈皮  你看
Oh. That's... that's Happy. Look.
他把他的房间给梅姨了  他就只能睡这下面了
He gave his room to May, so he's sleeping down here.
问你个奇怪的问题
I have a weird question.
你对这一切有没有感到释然
Does any part of you feel relieved about all of this?
从我被那只蜘蛛咬了之后...
Ever since I got bit by that Spider...
我只过了一周正常的生活
I've only had one week, where my life has felt normal.
或者说算得上正常吧  我猜
Or kind of normal, I guess
然后...
And...
那一周就是你发现我身份的时候
That was when you found out.
因为那时  我希望我身边能知道真相的人
Because then, everyone that was in my life
都知道了
that I wanted to know, knew.
这样就刚刚好
And it was perfect.
但现在变成了众人皆知  而...
But now everybody knows. And...
我成为了万众瞩目的焦点...
I am the most famous person in the entire world...
...尽管如此我仍旧家徒四壁
... and I'm still broke.
我...很期待明天和你见面
I'm... excited to see you tomorrow.
嗯  我也是
Yeah, me too.
别聊了
Wrap it up.
你们俩情投意合  我们都懂的  快挂了
You both like each other. We get it. Hang up.
再怎么聊也没有新创意的  明白吗  我可是要睡足八小时的
There's no new ground being broken. Okay? I need my eight hours.
-你一直都在听我们聊天吗   -嗨  哈皮
-Have you been listening this whole time?   -Hi, Happy.
你以为我想听啊
Not by choice.
MJ和你打招呼呢
MJ says hi.
晚上好
Hello.
直播放送  中城高中著名学子返校  开启高三之旅
We're covering the first day of senior year for Midtown High's most famous student,
彼得·帕克  冲呀  老虎
Peter Parker! Go get 'em, Tiger!
或者我该说  小蜘蛛
Or should I say, Spider?
人群蜂拥而至
The crowd has continued to grow here all
整个早晨  中城高中被围堵得水泄不通
morning long at the Midtown School of Science...
目前聚集的人群一分为二
The crowd seems evenly divided
一半支持蜘蛛侠  另一半则是在抗议
between supporters of Spider-Man, and protesters.
MJ  MJ看这边  我们爱你
MJ! MJ, we love you.
MJ  你准备要给他生一窝小蜘蛛吗
MJ, are you gonna have his spider-babies?
后退  后退  后退
Back up. Back up. Back up!
MJ  你知道他是杀人凶手对不对
MJ, you know he is the murderer right?
彼得  跟我拍个抖音视频
Peter. Do a TikTok with me.
-神秘客万岁  你这个杀人凶手   -给我们来个空翻
-Mysterio forever! Murderer!   -Do a flip!
-嘿  你跟MJ亲一个   -滚啊
-Hey, let's see you and MJ kiss!   -Back off!
你是谁啊
Who are you?
我是内德·利兹
I'm Ned Leeds.
-我是蜘蛛侠的...好朋友   -彼得·帕克的好朋友
-I'm Spider-Man's... best friend.    -Peter Parker's best friend.
你敢惹我兄弟  就是跟我"闪电"·汤普森过不去
You come at my boy? You come at Flash Thompson.
想了解我们振奋人心的友谊吗
You wanna read about our inspiring friendship?
可以读读我的新书《闪点》
You can now from my new book, Flashpoint.
朋友一生一起走  数不清的疯狂回忆  走过路过不要错过
One spider, two hearts, a million crazy-ass memories. Check it out.
蜘蛛侠  MJ  看这边
Spider-Man, MJ, look over here.
-走 走  快进去   -不  我还要等她
-Go. Go. go. go. Go!   -No, I gotta wait...
我们里面见  好吗
I'll see you inside, okay?
敬请关注中城新闻  我们将为您带来年度最新的独家报道
Keep watching Midtown News all year as we bring you upclose and personal coverage
那就是  彼得·帕克即将面临今年最难决战：申请大学
of Peter fighting his biggest battle yet: college admissions.
彼得
Peter.
我们...
We would love to...
欢迎你回到...
Welcome you back...
中城高中
To Midtown High.
英雄养成宝地
Where we shape heroes.
-啊哈   -或者说是杀人犯
-Uh-huh.   -Or murderers.
住嘴吧你
Stop it.
为你效劳是我的们的无上荣幸...
It's an honor to serve you...
-先生   -不对啊
-Sir.   -It's not!
神秘客说得对
Mysterio was right.
-停  我们不... 就这样吧   -神秘客是对的
-Stop. We don't... that's all.  -Mysterio was right.
有些同学给你弄了这个
Some of the students put this together for you.
才不是  是你整的吧
No. You did that.
-就是你   -我就帮了点忙而已  -哇哦
-You did that.   -I helped a little bit.  -Oh wow.
我好几次试图阻止他  但没成功
I tried to stop him so many times, but you powered through.
-这些都是他弄的   -干得漂亮
-He did all of that.   -You did a great job.
我希望你有时间的话可以停下来看一看...
I hope you have time to stop and check it out...
你想走就走...
And feel free to walk...
-或者从走廊荡过去...   -没错
-Or, or swing through the hallway...   -Yeah.
-或者从天花板爬过去  躲开其他人也行啦   -没错
-Or crawl on the ceiling to avoid everybody.   -Yeah.
我们相信你可以的
We all know you can do it.
那我就打算...
I'm just gonna...
-我知道你做了什么   -你别哪壶不开提哪壶了
-I know what you did.   -Stop it. You're embarassing yourself.
我就是知道...
Know what you did...
他就爱信阴谋论
He's a conspiracy theorist.
我们能不能   就在这上面待一整天呢
Can we just like, stay up here all day?
-下面太疯狂了  -等一下  看看这条
-It is so crazy down there.   -Wait, this one's good.
有人说
Some suggest that,
帕克的超能力包括雄蛛特有的催眠雌性功能
Parker's powers include the male spider's ability to hypnotize females.
-他借此色诱琼斯-沃森   -什么鬼
-Which he used to seduce Jones-Watson   -What?
-使其无可救药地爱上邪恶的他   -得了吧  别念了
-into his cult of personality.   -Come on. Stop.
你别念了行吗
Will you stop?
遵命  我的蜘蛛大人
Yes, my Spider-lord.
总算有点私人空间了
Finally. Some privacy.
下面真的太疯狂了
It is so crazy down there.
话说回来  我在想...
So, I was thinking...
等我们进了麻省理工
When we get into MIT,
我们应该住在一块
we should live together.
可以啊
Yeah, for sure.
嗯  我觉得行
Yeah. Love that.
-这将是我们的未来生活   -是的
-This is gonna be us.   -Yes.
除开那个飞盘  还有笑脸
Minus the frisbee. And the smiling.
麻省理工是我们的梦中情校...
MIT's obviously the dream...
但如果我们都再申请一样的保底学校
But if we match-up our backup schools,
到时候不管怎样  我们都能一起去波士顿
either way, we'll all be together in Boston.
新的学校  新的城市  我在那儿也能当蜘蛛侠
New school, new town. I can Spider-Man there.
-波士顿那儿肯定也有违法犯罪啥的   -对对对  肯定有
-I mean they have crime in Boston, right?   -Yes. Yes, they do.
没错  那种相当恶劣的犯罪
Yeah, wicked crime.
对吧  这是一个全新的开始
Yeah, so it'll be like a fresh start.
怎么了
What's up?
我也说不好  我就是感觉如果你不...
I don't know. I just feel like if you don't...
如果你做好会失望的准备
If you expect disappointment,
那你就永远不会真的失望
then you can never really get disappointed.
振作点
Come on.
全新的开始呢
It'll be a fresh start.
我们三个一起
And, we'll all be together.
没错  你说得对
Yeah. You're right.
-新的开始   -没错
-Fresh start.   -Yeah.
新的开始
Fresh start.
第一封回信送到了
First one's here!
没关系  这只是个保底的学校
It's okay. It's a backup school.
彼得
Peter?
没过吗
No?
最后一个了
Last one.
麻省理工的吗
MIT?
好了
Okay.
-准备好了吗?   -琼斯...
-Ready?   -Jones...
我不是让你把万圣节装饰都拆下来吗..
I told you to take down the Halloween decorations...
其实你是叫萨沙去拆的  所以...
Actually, that was Sasha, so...
废话少说  你照做就是了
Enough attitude, just do it.
这就去
On it.
-我紧张得要吐了   -憋着
-I feel like I'm gonna puke.   -Well, don't.
不然老板还得让我打扫
Because, he will just make me clean it.
这是我们唯一的机会了
This is our only shot.
要么上岸  要么完蛋
It's here, or nowhere.
嘿  乐观一点
Hey! Come on.
-好吧  你们准备好了吗   -准备好了
-Okay. You guys ready?   -Yeah.
好的  我数到三
Okay. On three.
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
被拒了
No.
我也  你呢
No. You?
"鉴于最近发生的争议  我们目前无法
"In light of recent controversy, we are unable to
考虑你的申请"
consider your application at this time."
这太不公平了
This is so not fair.
我是说这太不公平了  我没做错什么
I mean, this is so not fair. I didn't do anything wrong.
你们俩更没有做错什么
And you guys definitely didn't do anything wrong.
如果你做好会失望的准备  你就永远不会真的失望
Expect disappointment, and you will never get disappointed.
今夜无眠  波-波-
No sleep till Bo-Bo-
波-波-波士顿我来了!
Bo-Bo-Boston!
你们没被录取吗
You guys didn't get in?
对啊  因为我们是蜘蛛侠的真朋友
Yeah. Because we're actually friends with Spider-Man.
呃  对了...
Uhh, yeah...
我该走了  我有一场新生联谊会要参加...
I better get going. There's a, mixer for new admissions...
抱歉了...伙计们
And... sorry, guys.
琼斯  你干嘛呢  快给我去干活
Jones, what are you doing? Get back to work.
好的  来了
Yeah. Coming.
你知道吗
You know what?
再来一次  我还是会做同样的选择
I wouldn't change a thing I did.
我也一样
Me neither.
不过我还是得把这封信拿给爸妈看
Although, I could just showed this letter to my parents.
呃...
Umm....
嗨
Hi.
Hi!
我是...
I'm...
世界上最出名的人  我知道你
The most famous person in the world. I know.
我是王  小心别滑倒  我们这儿可没有职工责任险
Wong. Try not to slip. We don't have liability insurance.
-这是准备办一场假日派对吗?   -不是
-Is all this for a holiday party?   -No.
有个传送门是连通西伯利亚的
One of the rotunda gateways connects to Siberia.
暴风雪刮进来了
Blizzard blasted through.
因为某人忘了每个月施一次维护咒把门封严实了
Because someone forgot to cast monthly maintenance spell to keep the seals tight.
没错  就是他忘了  因为他忘了我现在有更重要的责任
That's right. He did. Because he forgot I now have higher duties.
更重要的责任
Higher duties?
至尊法师有更重要的责任  没错
The Sorcerer Supreme has higher duties, yes.
等下  我以为你才是至尊法师
Wait, I thought you were the Sorcerer Supreme?
现在理论上来讲他才是
No. He got it on a technicality
因为我被烁灭了五年
'cause I blipped for five years.
哦  好吧  恭喜
Oh. Well, congratulations.
如果我当时在的话  那我...
If I'd been here, then I'd...
早就把这里烧没了
Burned the place down.
你俩继续  我没叫你们停下呢
You two, no one said stop shoveling.
所以彼得...
So, Peter...
什么风把你吹来了
To what do I owe the pleasure?
对了  嗯...
Right. Umm...
很抱歉打扰你  先生  但是...
I'm really sorry to bother you, sir, but...
拜托  我们一起拯救了半个宇宙诶
Please. We saved half the universe together.
你不用那么客气叫我先生
I think we're beyond calling me sir.
好吧  呃...史蒂芬
Okay, uhh... Stephen.
感觉怪怪的  但我允许你这么叫
That feels weird, but I'll allow it.
当...
When...
当神秘客泄露我身份的时候
When Mysterio revealed my identity...
我的整个生活被搅得一团糟
My entire life got screwed up, and...
我就在想  虽然我也不知道这样可不可行
I was wondering, I mean, I don't even know if this would actually work,
但我在想  如果...
but I was wondering if...
也许你能穿越到过去然后阻止这一切发生呢
Maybe you could go back in time and make it so that he never did?
彼得
Peter
我们扰乱了时空的稳定性  复活了无数的生命
we tampered with the stability of space-time to resurrect countless lives.
你想再来一次  就因为你的生活出了岔子
You wanna do it again now just because yours got messy?
这不是...为了我  我是说  这件事真的伤害了很多人
This isn't... it's not about me. I mean, this is really hurting a lot of people.
我的...
My...
我的梅姨  哈皮...
My Aunt May, Happy...
还有我的死党  我女朋友  他们的未来都被毁了
My best friend, my girlfriend, their futures are ruined just
仅仅因为他们认识我  而且...
because they know me, and...
他们没有做错什么
They've done nothing wrong.
我很抱歉  但是...
I am so sorry, but...
即使我愿意这么做
even if I wanted to...
时间宝石也已经不在我这儿了
I don't have the Time Stone anymore.
也是哦
That's right.
抱歉...打扰你了
I'm really sorry if I... wasted your time.
-没事儿...   -当我没问过吧
-No, you didn't...   -Just forget about it please.
放心吧  他记性差着呢
He will. He's really good at forgetting things.
王  你倒让我想起个好主意
Wong. You've actually generated a good idea.
啥
What?
卡夫卡符咒
The runes of Kof-Kol.
哦  就是个普通的遗忘咒语
Oh, it's just a standard spell of forgetting.
不会逆转时间  但至少能让别人忘记你是蜘蛛侠
Won't turn back time, but at least people will forget that you were ever Spider-Man.
-真的么   -不 别当真
-Seriously?   -No. Not seriously.
那个咒语穿越已知和未知现实之间的黑暗边界
That spell travels the dark borders between known and unknown reality.
它很危险
It's too dangerous.
天哪  咱不是为了一点儿小事就用过吗
God, we've used it for a lot less.
你还记得卡玛泰姬的满月派对吗
Do you remember the full moon party in Kamar-Taj?
-不记得   -你看
-No.   -Exactly.
拜托  老王
Come on. Wong.
你瞧他都这么惨了
Hasn't he been through enough?
出事儿了别再找我擦屁股
Just leave me out of this.
不找就不找
Fine.
得
这是什么地方
So what is this place?
至圣所建在宇宙能流交汇处
The Sanctum's built at the intersection of cosmic energy currents.
我们最先发现了这地方
We were the first to seek them out.
这里有些墙体已有数千年历史了
Some of these walls are thousands of years old.
80年代还有人在这儿拍摄过电影《伸冤人》呢
And they shot an episode of Equalizer here in the 80's.
呃  我...
Well, I, umm...
我非常感谢你为我这么做  先生
really appreciate you doing this for me, sir.
没关系
Don't mention it.
也不用叫我先生
And don't call me sir.
哦对  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
准备好了吗
You ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
很高兴认识你  蜘蛛侠
Nice knowing you, Spider-Man.
等下  你说啥
Wait, excuse me?
全世界都要忘记彼得·帕克就是蜘蛛侠
The entire world is about to forget that Peter Parker is Spider-Man.
-包括我在内   -所有人吗
-Including me.   -Everyone?
不能留几个例外吗
Can't some people still know?
咒语不是这样用的
That's not how the spell works.
施法过程很难随意改变  而且异常危险
Very difficult and dangerous to change it mid-casting.
那我女朋友也会忘记我们的种种过往吗
So my girlfriend is just gonna forget about everything we've been through?
我是说  那样她还是我女朋友吗
I mean, is she even gonna be my girlfriend?
这取决于她喜欢的是蜘蛛侠还是彼得
That depends. Was she your girlfriend just because you're Spider-Man, or...
我不知道  希望是彼得
I don't know. I really hope not.
好吧  满足你
Alright. Fine.
全世界所有人都会忘记你就是蜘蛛侠  除了...
Everyone in the world is gonna forget you're Spider-Man, except...
你女朋友
your girlfriend.
太谢谢你了...
Thank you so much....
噢天哪  还有内德
Oh, my God. Ned.
内德
Ned!
内德又是哪个
What is a Ned?
他是我死党  我也不想让他忘记我
He's my best friend so it's really important to me that Ned knows.
行吧
Okay.
在我做法的时候别再更改
Let's not change the parameters of the spell anymore...
-咒语参数了   -好的  下不为例
-While I'm casting it.   -Okay, I'm done. I swear I'm done.
但是梅姨也要记得我啊
But my Aunt May should really know.
彼得  别再篡改咒语了
Peter, stop tampering with the spell.
之前当她发现我是蜘蛛侠  情况真的很难办啊
Once she found out that I was Spider-Man, it was really messy, and
我可受不了再来一次
I don't think that I can go through with that again.
-所以算上梅姨了吗   -算
-So, my Aunt May?   -Yes!
-哦  太谢谢了 还有哈皮呢   -不  我不嗨皮我很烦
-Oh, thank you. Happy?   -No. I am annoyed.
不不  这是个昵称  哈罗德·"哈皮"·霍根
No, it's a nickname. Harold "Happy" Hogan.
他曾经和托尼·斯塔克一起工作  然后在...
He used to work with Tony Stark, then he tried dating...
-跟我梅姨约会   -你丫能闭嘴了吗
-My aunt May.   -Could you just stop talking?
基本上  原来就知道我真实身份的人都不该忘
Basically, everyone who knew that I was Spider-Man before, should still know.
-这就成功了吗   -才怪
-Did it work?   -No.
-你六度篡改我的咒语   -五次
-You changed my spell six times.   -Five times.
你改了我的咒语  我明明告诉过你这样不行的
You changed my spell. You don't do that. I told you,
因此
and that is why.
咒语完全失控  要是我没停下的话
That spell was completely out of control. If I hadn't shut it down,
可能会引发灾难
something catastrophic could've happened.
-史蒂芬  对此我实在抱歉...   -叫我先生
-Stephen, listen, I am so sorry...   -Call me sir.
对不起  先生
Sorry, sir.
自从我们一起经历了那些事情  不知何故  我总是会忘记
You know, after everything we've been through together, somehow I always forget...
你只是个孩子
You're just a kid.
听着  帕克  其实
Look, Parker, the problem,
问题不在于神秘客
it's not Mysterio.
而在于你自己  你过着两种截然不同的生活
It's you. Trying to live two different lives.
时间越长就越危险  相信我
And the longer you do that, the more dangerous it becomes. Believe me.
我很抱歉你和朋友们
I'm so sorry about, you and your friends,
没能去上大学  但如果大学真的拒绝你们的话
not getting into college, but if they rejected you, and...
那你就去说服校方再三斟酌  此外别无他法
you try to convince them to reconsider, there is nothing else you can do.
"说服他们"
When you say "convince them",
-你是说  我可以联系他们   -对啊
-you mean like, I could've called them?   -Yeah.
还有这种操作吗
I can do that?
你都没联系过吗
You haven't called?
呃  我收到了他们的来信  就以为...
Well, I mean, I got their letter, and I assumed that...
我打断一下  你是说
I'm sorry, but are you telling me,
你都没先想着去找他们谈谈
that you didn't even think to plead your case with them first,
就来让我给全世界洗脑吗
before you asked me to brainwash the entire world?
你要是这么说的话  那么...
I mean, when you put it like that, then...
拜托  快接电话  快接啊...
Come on. Pick up, pick up, pick up...
老兄怎么啦  我很忙的
Dude, what? I'm busy.
闪电  麻省理工的联谊会在哪儿举办来着
Flash, where's the MIT mixer?
-问这个干嘛   -我得去找人谈谈
-Why?   -Because, I need to come and talk to someone.
我想去为内德和MJ争取读书的机会
I'm trying to get Ned and MJ a second chance at getting in.
这对我有啥好处呢
What's in it for me?
光是和你通话就很冒险了
I'm risking a lot just talking to you.
好吧  我能...
Okay. I will....
连续一星期荡蛛丝送你上学
Pick you up and swing you to school for a week?
一个月
For a month.
一星期
For a week.
-两星期   -拜托了  闪电  帮帮忙好不
-Two weeks.   -Flash, please. Come on, help me.
你知道我要的是什么
You know what I want.
行吧  我会告诉大家你是我最好的朋友
Okay, I'll tell everyone that you're my best friend.
闪电  求求你告诉我
Flash, please help me.
成交  成交  有这么一位女士
Cool, cool, cool. So there's this lady.
她是那儿的助理副校长  你可以去求她帮忙
She's the assistant vice chancellor. You can plead your case with her.
很好  棒极了  她在哪儿
Okay, perfect. Where is she?
-她走了   -到哪去了
-She left.   -To go where?
机场
To the airport.
斯塔克网络  无法访问
Stark Network, unavailable.
面部识别  无法启用
Facial recognition, unavailable.
嗨
Hi.
对  我看得见你
Yep. I can see you.
-是彼得·帕克   -老妈
-And that's Peter Parker.   -Mom?
-嘿   -妈妈
-Hey.   -Mommy.
好吧
Okay.
怎么了
Yeah.
嗨  我是彼得·帕克...
Hi. I'm Peter Parker...
你知道你现在车流中  对吧
You do know you're in the street, right?
我知道  对不起  我只是  我真的得
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry. I just, I really needed to
跟您谈谈  我知道您正要去机场
talk to you, I know you're on your way to the airport...
MJ·沃森和内德·利兹是我这辈子认识的最聪明的两个人
MJ Watson and Ned Leeds are the two smartest people I've ever met in my entire life,
我是最笨的那个  因为...
and I'm the dumbest person, because....
我让他们帮我  但如果我没让他们帮我
I let them help me, but if I didn't let them help me.
会有成千上万的人死去  所以求求您  别让...
then millions of people would've died, so please don't...
别让麻省理工像我一样愚蠢而错失两位人才
Don't let MIT be dumb like me.
-你说麻省理工愚蠢   -不是
-MIT is dumb?   -No!
我是说别让它变蠢
I'm saying don't let MIT be dumb.
我是说  就是...
I mean, like the...
不让他们去  那就是比我还蠢
the dumber version of me that wouldn't have let them help.
你没有提前准备一番吧  彼得
You didn't rehearse that, did you, Peter?
总的来说  我想说的是...
Basically, what I'm trying to...
你为什么跑啊  怎么了...
Why are you running? What...
哦  我的天  女士  您得赶紧下车了
Oh, my God. Ma'am? You should get out of the car.
所有人离开大桥
Everybody get off the bridge!
车门被锁住了  车门...嘿
The door is locked. Door's... Hey!
你好啊  彼得
Hello, Peter.
嗨
Hi?
我们...我们认识吗
Have we... Do I know you?
你对我的机器做了什么
What have you done with my machine?
你的机...我不知道你在说什么  什么机器
Your ma... I don't know what you're talking about. I don't know. What machine?
太阳的能量  就掌握在我的手中  它不见了
The power of the sun, in the palm of my hand. It's gone.
听我说  先生  如果你不到处砸车的话
Listen, sir. If you stop smashing cars,
我们可以合作  我可以帮你找你的机器
we could work together and I can help you find your machine.
想玩游戏吗
You wanna play games?
接着
Catch!
好了  你们没事了  你们安全了  快离开这儿
It's okay. You guys are good, you're safe. Get out of here.
你以为你的炫酷新战衣能救你吗
You think your fancy new suit's gonna save you?
当初我就应该抓住机会杀了你的小女友
I should've killed your little girlfriend when I had the chance.
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say?
看来我们是棋逢对手了
Looks like we got competition.
彼得  救命
Peter! Help!
别怕  女士  我这就来
Don't worry, Ma'am! I'm coming!
彼得
Peter!
女士  请你保持冷静
Ma'am, just stay calm.
-深呼吸  你还好吗   -不好
-Just take a deep breath. Are you okay?   -No!
一切都在我的控制之中
I've got it. I've got it all under control.
战衣破损
Suit compromised.
纳米科技
Nanotechnology.
你真是超乎我的意料  彼得
You've outdone yourself, Peter.
是我低估了你
I underestimated you.
但是现在  你要死了
But now, you die.
你不是彼得·帕克
You're not Peter Parker.
我现在真是一头雾水
I am so confused right now.
这是怎么回事
What's happening?
检测到新设备
New device detected.
新设备配对中
Pairing new device.
别听他的  你们要听我的
Don't listen to him, you listen to me.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  嘿  听我的
Hey. Hey! Listen to me.
不  不是他  听我的
No, not him. Me!
女士  你还好吗  快走  你还能赶上飞机
Ma'am are you okay? Come on, you can still make your flight.
彼得
Peter.
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
不是  呃  我...
No. Well, I'm...
不是的  我...
No, I'm...
我会和招生办说说你朋友的事
I'm gonna talk to admissions about your friends,
还有你的事
and I'm gonna talk to them about you.
不  但是  夫人  重点不在我
No, but, Ma'am, this isn't about me.
我会和他们提起你的朋友  还有你
I'm going to talk to them about your friends, and you.
-好吗   -真的吗
-Okay?   -Really?
如果你能安安分分不惹事
And if you keep your noses clean,
说不定你也会有很大的机会
maybe you'll have a fair shot.
好了  让开  我要会会那个男人
Here. Get out of the way. Let me get that man.
嘿  你  我看见你了
Hey. You. I see you.
滚过来
Come here!
你个挨千刀的
That was not okay.
太离谱了
Unbelievable.
你别想着杀我了
Until you stop trying to kill me,
现在是我在控制  老兄
I'm in control, buddy.
我能控制你这一整套触手系统
Of this whole tentacle situation you got going on here.
明白吗  现在告诉我  你是谁  这是怎么回...
Okay? Now, who are you? What is going on...
奥斯本
Osborn?
博士...
Doctor...
许愿的时候小心一点  帕克
Be careful what you wish for, Parker.
放我出去
Let me out of here!
你能不能跟我解释一下这到底是怎么回事
Can you please explain to me what is going on?
你随意施放的那个能让所有人忘记
That little spell that you botched where you wanted everyone to forget
彼得·帕克是蜘蛛侠的小咒语  它开始把每个宇宙中
that Peter Parker is Spider-Man, it started pulling in everyone who knows
所有知道彼得·帕克是蜘蛛侠的人  拉进这个宇宙里
Peter Parker is Spider-Man, from every universe, into this one.
从每个宇宙中
From every universe?
你是谁  我这是在哪儿
Who are you? Where am I?
我认为我们最好不要与他们有所交集  因为说实话
I think it's better if we don't engage with them because, frankly,
关于多元宇宙这一概念
the Multiverse is a concept about which we know
我们知之甚少
frighteningly little.
多元宇宙竟然是真的
The multiverse is real.
这本应是不可能的
This shouldn't even be possible.
但我以为你中止施咒了
But I thought you stopped the spell?
没有  我只是把咒语控制住了  但现在看来  依然有漏网之鱼
No, I contained it, but it would appear that a few of them squeaked through.
你离开以后  我发现了另一个世界的来客
After you left, I detected an otherworldly presence.
我追着它到了下水道
I pursued it into the sewers,
在那儿发现了这坨又黏又绿的鬼东西
where I found that slimy, green, son of a gun.
咒语
Spell?
这是魔法吗
Is it magic?
现在是什么情况  谁的生日派对吗
What is this, a birthday party?
这小丑又是谁
Who is this clown?
到底发生了什么
What is this madness?
看好了  你认识名叫彼得·帕克  绰号是蜘蛛侠的人吗
Watch this. Do you know a Peter Parker who is Spider-Man?
我认识
Yes.
-那这是他吗   -不是
-Is that him?   -No.
明白没
See?
好了  我们得这么做
Okay, here's what we gotta do.
我不清楚到底有多少这样的...
I don't know how many of these
-..."访客"   -我在桥上
-visitors we got...   -I saw another one.
还见到了另一个
On the bridge.
他看起来像一个...
He was like a...
会飞的绿妖精
Like a flying green elf.
好吧  听起来他似乎怪可爱的  你要不就从他开始查起吧
Well he sounds jolly. Why don't you start with him?
我需要你把他们抓到这儿来
I need you to capture them and bring them here,
同时我会弄清楚怎么把他们送回去
while I figure out how to get them back.
免得他们破坏现实的结构  或者再不济
Before they destroy the fabric of reality, or worse,
被王发现了
Wong finds out.
奇异博士
Uhh, Doctor Strange?
怎么了
What?
我和我的朋友们刚获得了进麻省理工的第二次机会
My friends and I just got a second chance at getting into MIT.
如果让学校看到我和这些怪物打来打去的...
If the school sees me fighting these crazy monsters...
-嘿  嘴巴给我放干净点   -抱歉
-Hey, watch your mouth!   -I'm sorry.
认真的吗  这时候了还想着上大学
Seriously? Still talking about college?
-你刚才做了什么   -这个
-Hey, what did you just do?   -This.
你怎么做到的
How did you do that?
这叫日积月累  学有所成
Lots of birthday parties.
嘿
Hey!
这么一发射  把他抓进来  然后这事儿就翻篇了  不用谢
One shot, send him here and move on. You're welcome.
开始行动吧
Get to work.
先生
Sir?
又怎么了
Now what?
我知道这是我的烂摊子  我向你保证
I know this is my mess, and I swear to you
我会处理好它的  但是我需要一些帮助
that I'll fix it, but I'm gonna need some help.
我真不敢相信我居然进了至尊圣所
I can't believe I'm in the Sanctum Sanctorum.
呵呵我也是
Neither can I.
所以...
So...
你是怎么知道自己会魔法的  因为我奶奶说过
How did you know you're made of magic? Because my nanna says
我们家族有家传天赋  而且有时我会感觉手有点刺痛...
that we have it in our family and sometimes I get these tinglings in my hand...
那你该去看看医生了
You should talk to your physician.
彼得
Peter!
-嘿   -嘿
-Hey!   -Hey.
我很抱歉把你们给扯进来了
I'm so sorry for dragging you in this,
但我需要你们帮我一起找到这些家伙...
you just gotta help me find these guys...
你不需要道歉  好吗  你给了我们去麻省理工的第二次机会
You don't have to apologize. Okay? You got us a second shot at MIT.
这些坏人是怎么到这儿来的
So, how did the bad guys get here?
为了让你们能够有书读  他把我的咒语搞得一团糟
He screwed up a spell trying to get you into college.
-慢着  我以为是因为你救了那位女士   -你用魔法帮的我们啊
-Wait, what? I thought it was the MIT lady you saved.   -You did it with magic?
救人是施法之后的事了  我们先关注下好消息吧  行吗
No, that was after. Let's just focus on the good news, okay?
不行  我们还是关注下坏消息吧
No, let's just focus on the bad news.
因为到现在  你连一个多元宇宙入侵者都没发现  所以...
As of now, you have detected zero multiversal trespassers, so...
拿出你们的手机
Get on your phones,
搜索全网  然后...
scour the internet, and...
搞定这个烂摊子
Scooby-Doo this shit!
你在指挥我们做事吗
You're telling us what to do,
而这一切都是你的咒语造成的
even though it was your spell,
也就是说  其实主要责任在你
that got screwed up. Meaning that all of this is kind of your mess.
这么说吧  我知道
You know, I know
几个魔法用语  而第一个呢  就是"拜托"
a couple of magic words myself, starting with the word 'please'.
那拜托啦  给我搞定这烂摊子
Please, Scooby-Doo this shit.
你们可以用地下工作室
You can work in the undercraft.
地下工作室
The undercraft?
酷毙了啊
Badass.
伙计们  听好了  关于咒语这件事...
Guys, listen. About this whole spell thing...
完全没问题的
It's totally okay.
-真的吗   -是的
-Wait, really?   -Yeah.
我明白  你只是想...
I mean, I get it. You were...
解决问题罢了...
just trying to fix things...
那...
And so...
或许下次提前知会我们一声
Maybe just run it by us next time, you know?
这样一来  当你想着"嘿  我要做些会...
That way, when you're thinking, "Hey, I'm about to do something that could...
破坏宇宙的事儿"时  我们就能帮上忙了
break the universe", we could like, help you.
一起讨论  或者...
Workshop something, or...
头脑风暴之类的
brainstorm ideas.
没问题
Deal.
内德呢
Ned?
一声"兄弟"大过天  说真的  这没什么大不了的
Oh, dude. I don't care. And seriously, not a big deal.
是酷刑架
A torture rack.
那是普拉提机
That is a pilates machine.
-而这是...   -地牢
-That is...   -The crypt.
好的  那我们得找到剩下的穿越者
Okay, so we get the rest of the guys.
你只用"嗞"他们一下  那位魔法博士会把他们送回去的
You zap them, Doctor Magic will send them back.
然后等我们进了麻省理工
And when we get into MIT,
我请你们吃变味儿的甜甜圈
round of stale donuts, my treat.
一起去抓多元宇宙穿越者吧
Let's catch some multiverse men.
嘿
Hey!
这俩是谁
Who the hell are these two?
他们是我的朋友  这是MJ  这是内德
These are my friends. This is MJ and this is Ned.
你好
Hello.
不好意思  你叫什么来着
I'm sorry, what was your name again?
我是奥托·奥克塔维斯博士
Dr. Otto Octavius.
等下  说真的  你的真名是啥
Wait, no seriously, what's your actual name?
噢  那是恐龙吗
Oh, is that a dinosaur?
如果油漆洗不掉  就把它带来收容所  我来帮你洗
If the paint won't come off, bring it by the shelter. I'll get it out.
不不不  梅姨
No, no, no, May.
我们得先找到这些人
We gotta find these guys first.
好吧  那就先完成你的任务  然后再过来
Well, finish your mission, then come by.
我们要举办罐头食品活动
We are having a canned food drive.
-这样可以诶   -我找到了一个  我找到了一个
-That could work.   -I got one, I got one, I got one.
-梅姨  我得走了   -好的  爱你呦  拜拜
-Oh, May? I gotta go.   -Okay. Love you. Bye.
人是死的
I mean you can take the guy out of the chair
办法是活的
but you can't take the chair out of the guy.
你找到什么了
What did you find?
呃...
There's a...
城外一处军事研究设施发生了骚乱
disturbance near a military research facility outside of the city.
据目击者称  有怪物在天上飞
And witnesses say they saw a monster flying through the air.
肯定是我在桥上看到的那个家伙  对吧
That's gotta be the guy I saw on the bridge, right?
这不可能
That's impossible.
你认识他  对吗
You know him, don't you?
在桥上的时候  你叫了他的名字
On the bridge, you said his name.
诺曼·奥斯本
Norman Osborn.
一名出色的科学家
Brilliant scientist.
军事研究专家
Military researcher.
但他贪婪成性
But he was greedy.
最终误入歧途
Misguided.
-他怎么了   -我们真是受够你的问题了  小子
-What happened to him?   -We tire of your questions, boy!
好吧...
Okay...
我得走了  是哪来着
I gotta go. Where am I going?
那不可能是他的
It can't be him.
为什么
Why?
因为诺曼·奥斯本几年前就死了
Because Norman Osborn died years ago.
所以要么我们看到的是别人
So either we saw someone else,
要么就是你将遁入黑暗  和鬼魂斗智斗勇
or you're flying out into the darkness, to fight a ghost.
盯好这片树林  我们还不知道那人在哪
Keep an eye out on those trees, we don't really know where this guy is.
真不知道你怎么能在这种情况下还不呕吐的
I genuinely don't know how you do this without throwing up.
你们看到了吗
Did you guys see that?
-啥都没看到   -乌漆嘛黑的
-No.   -It's, it's really dark.
发生什么了
What's happening?
彼得  怎么了
Peter, what is it?
你的蜘蛛第六感来了吗
Are you getting the tingle thing?
是你的蜘蛛感应起作用了吗
Is the tingle thing happening? Is your tingle tingling?
你们看到了吗
Are you guys seeing this?
看到了
Yeah.
-奥斯本   -不
-Osborn?   -No.
他是绿的  这个人是蓝的
He was green. This guy's blue.
你不会碰巧来自另一个宇宙吧
You wouldn't happen to be from another universe, would you?
他在干嘛
What's he doing?
不知道  看起来像是在充电
I don't know. Looks like he's charging.
看着不太妙啊  快网住他吧
I don't like this. Just web him.
往左  左边  对对
Go left, left! Go left! Yes！
别瞎指挥  等会  往右  右边
What are you talking about? Wait! Right, right!
-伙计们   -别听他的
-Guys!   -Don't listen to him.
你们这是帮倒忙啊
This is not helping!
哦不  发生什么了
No, no, no. What happened?
彼得  彼得
Peter? Peter?
哇哦
Whoa.
彼得  是我  弗林特·马尔科  你记得吗
Peter, it's me. Flint Marko. You remember?
我是彼得  但是不是你认识的彼得
I'm Peter, but I'm not your Peter.
你不是我认识的彼得  什么意思  发生什么了
What do you mean you're not my Peter? What the hell is going on?
我会跟你解释的  但能不能先帮我阻止那个家伙
I'll explain everything, but first can you help me stop this guy?
好的
Okay.
你尽量包围他  我去把电给断了
You try to surround him and I'll pull the plug.
好的  上吧
All right, let's go.
我快坚持不住了
I can't hold him much longer.
我来了  好了
I got him. I got it.
不一样的彼得  奇奇怪怪
Different Peter. Weird.
谢啦
Thanks.
-不好意思   -问题不大
-Sorry.   -Don't worry about it.
我的身体恢复了
I got my body back.
嘿  呃...
Hey, umm...
这听上去很扯  但是...
This is gonna sound really crazy, but...
这不是你们所属的宇宙
this isn't your universe.
-另一个宇宙吗   -嗯哼
-Another universe?  -Uh huh.
-什么   -我刚刚就感受到了
-What?   -That's what I was feeling.
这股能量  截然不同
The power. It's different.
我很喜欢
I like it.
放轻松  伙计
Easy, buddy.
你们来到这里  其实是我的错
It's actually my fault that you're here.
你是说来到这个宇宙  还是树林啊
Like the universe? Or the woods?
-我恨树林   -我是说这个宇宙  先生
-I hate the woods.   -I meant the universe, sir.
所以要怎样  你们就看我光着屁股站在这吗
So what? You guys just gonna stand there and act like I ain't butt-ass naked?
-对哦   -呃  不是的  我...
-I am.   -Uhh, no, no... I...
那是什么
What was that?
-你对他做了什么  -不不  别担心  没事的
-What did you just do to him?   -No, no, no. It's okay. It's okay.
-你杀了他吗   -哇哦  听着
-Did you kill him?   -Whoa, listen.
我会解释一切  你相信我就好  求你了
I can explain everything. You just have to trust me, please.
我才不信你  我又不认识你
I don't trust you. I don't know you.
这是什么
What is this?
你站错队了
You picked the wrong side.
康纳斯
Connors?
什么
What?
你认识这个生物
You know this creature?
哦不不  不是什么生物  他是个人
No, no, no, no. Not a creature. A man.
他们来自同一个宇宙
From same universes.
科特·康纳斯博士  他是位科学家
Dr. Curt Connors. He was a scientist
跟我一样在奥氏集团工作
in Oscorp when I worked there.
他是个很出色的科学家
A brilliant scientist.
直到他把自己变成了一只蜥蜴
Till he turned himself into a lizard.
然后他想把整个城市的人都变成蜥蜴  真是疯了
Then he tried to turn the whole city into lizards. It was crazy.
不疯狂好吗  麦克斯  这就是人类进化的新方向
It wasn't crazy, Max. It was the next step in human evolution.
恐龙说话了
The dinosaur can talk.
-是蜥蜴   -哦对
-Lizard.   -Right.
那么  你又是怎么回事
Speaking of which, what happened to you?
我记得你之前  一口烂牙  是个四眼仔  头还秃了
Last I recall, you had bad teeth, glasses and a comb-over.
你是去整形了吗
Did you get a makeover?
你知道我可以给你来个真正的全身大整吧
You know I can give you a real makeover.
-让我猜猜看  是把我整成一只蜥蜴吗   -没错
-Let me guess. Into a lizard?   -Exactly.
你们俩能闭嘴吗  我们到底在哪
Could you two just shut up? Where are we?
-这事有点复杂   -一个巫师的地牢
-It's complicated.   -A wizard's dungeon.
巫师的...巫师的地牢
Wizard's... Wizard's dungeon?
没有别的好解释了
There's no real way to sugarcoat that.
这就是一个巫师的地牢
It's literally the dungeon of a wizard.
听着  我不抢你的魔法
Look, you can keep your magic.
我只想感受下之前的那股新能量
I want a taste of that new energy I just felt.
哦  彼得  嘿
Oh, Peter. Hey.
嘿  那些家伙过去了吗
Hey. Did those guys come through yet?
应该有一个电人和一个沙人
There should be an electric guy and a sand guy.
是的  他们都关在这儿
Yeah. They're all here and locked up.
太好了  我还要在这多待一会儿
Perfect. I'm gonna just stay here for a bit,
试着修复一下损坏的设施  省得他们又怪到我头上
and try to fix this damage so they don't blame it on me again.
-好的   -嘿  我想说...
-Okay.   -Hey, I...
没有你  这些我都办不到  所以...
I couldn't do any of this without you, so...
-谢谢你   -嗯呐  没事
-Thank you.   -Yeah, of course.
嘿  帮我问一下他  这是个树怪
Hey, ask him if this is like a tree monster,
还是一个变成树的科学家
or like a scientist that turned into a tree.
这不就是棵树吗  兄弟
Is this a tree, man?
那就是一棵树
That's a tree.
懦夫
Coward.
有个新的世界等着我们去征服
We have a new world to conquer.
-你让我感到恶心   -别烦我  求你了
-You make me sick.   -Leave me alone. Please.
躲藏在阴影里...
Hiding in the shadows...
-逃避真实的自己   -不
-Hiding from who you truly are.   -No!
你无法逃避真实的自己
You can't escape yourself!
-嘿  梅姨   -嘿  彼得
-Hey, May.   -Hey, Peter.
我正上班呢  呃...
I'm at work, and, umm...
你要找的一个人刚刚走了进来
One of the guys you're looking for just walked in.
梅姨  她在哪  谢谢
May? Where's May? Thank you.
嘿  他来了
Hey, here he is.
诺曼
Norman,
这是我的侄子
this is my nephew.
诺曼·奥斯本  我以为你已经...
Norman Osborn? I thought that you were...
我在这里的广告上看见了蜘蛛侠
I saw Spider-Man in an ad for this place.
于是我想着他能帮帮我
And I thought he could help me.
但你不是他
But you're not him.
等等  所以你想要蜘蛛侠的帮助
Wait, so you want Spider-Man's help?
他就这么走了进来
He just wandered in.
我不知道还能去哪
I didn't know where else to go.
我的房子里住着其他人
Someone's living in my house.
奥氏集团都不存在
Oscorp doesn't exist.
我的儿子...
My son...
有时候
Sometimes,
我甚至都不是我自己
I'm not myself.
我就好像...
I'm...
是另一个人
someone else.
而且每次他控制身体的时候  我就什么都记不得
And, everytime he's in control, I can't remember.
-现在我在这儿  在这个地方    -是谁呢
-And now, I'm here, in this place,   -Who is in control,
-诺曼  是谁在控制你...   -在这座城市  我也不知道...
-Norman, who is in control...   -in this city, I don't know...
-我不知道...我不知道我身上发生了什么   -没事
-and I don't know... I don't know what's going on with me.  -Okay.
-我没有...我不明白怎么回事   -嗯嗯
-I don't... It doesn't make sense.   -Yeah.
他迷失了
He's lost.
我并不是单指在这个宇宙
And I don't mean just in the cosmos.
他的脑子也不大清醒
I mean in his mind.
他们都是这个样子吗
Are they all like this?
是的
Yeah.
我的意思是  他们或多或少都有点精神上或身体上的问题
Well, I mean they all have their own, mental or physical issues.
哦  他需要帮助  也许他们都需要
Well, he needs help, but maybe they all do.
你该不会是想...不  梅姨  这...
What, you don't mean... No, May, this...
这不关我的事
This isn't my problem.
彼得  真的不关你的事吗
Peter, not your problem? Mmm?
梅姨...
May...
他们回去的话  得到帮助的可能性要大得多
Their chance of getting help is way better back where they came from.
把他们送回家
Sending them home,
这是我们能为他们做的最好的事情
That's the best thing that we can do for them.
为了他们
For them?
还是为了你自己
Or for yourself?
看看你周围
Look around you.
我们就是做这个的
This is what we do.
我们帮助他人
We help people.
把他们送回去  才是对他们最好的做法
This is what's best, for them.
相信我
Trust me.
但是事实依旧如此
But the fact remains,
蜘蛛侠是个威胁
Spider-Man is a menace!
广告之后  马上回来
We'll be right back,
号角牌每日营养补充剂
after a brief word from Daily Bugle supplements.
您的另一样每日所需
The only other Daily fix you need.
完毕
And, we're out.
什么
What?
我看见他们了
I got eyes on them.
他和他的阿姨  还有一个我不认识的人一起
He's with his aunt and some guy I don't know.
你确定吗
You sure?
他们正离开收容所
They're just leaving the shelter.
好的  不要跟丢他
Okay. Don't lose him.
谢谢你  梅
Thanks, May.
希望能再见到你
Hope to see you again.
嘿
Hey.
他信任你
He trusts you.
我也是
So do I.
多谢你帮我把战服洗干净
Thanks for cleaning my suit.
待会见
I'll see you later.
-伙计们  这是奥斯本先生   -嘿  是奥斯本博士
-Guys, this is Mr. Osborn.   -Hey, it's Doctor.
抱歉  呃...
Sorry. Umm...
奥斯本博士  他们是我的朋友  内德和MJ
Dr. Osborn, these are my friends, Ned and MJ.
玛丽·简
Mary Jane?
其实是米歇尔·琼斯
It's Michelle Jones, actually.
真是不可思议
Fascinating.
你们觉得还有其他内德·利兹们吗
Do you think there are other Ned Leedses?
奥克塔维斯
Octavius?
奥斯本
Osborn
-你...发生了什么   -你怎么会...
-What... What happened to you?   -What happened to...
-你真是一具行尸走肉   -你什么意思
-You're the walking corpse.   -What do you mean?
你已经死了  诺曼
You died, Norman.
很多年前就死了
Years ago.
你疯了
You're insane.
天哪  我喜欢这里
God, I love it here.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
-他就站在这里  他没…   -他死了
-He's standing right there. He's not...   -Dead.
他们都死了  在同蜘蛛侠的战斗中命丧黄泉
They both died fighting Spider-Man.
新闻已经公布他们的死讯了
It was all over the news.
绿魔呢
Green Goblin?
被你自己的滑翔机刺穿了
Impaled by the glider he flew around on.
接着几年后...
And a couple of years later...
你  章鱼博士
You. Doc Ock.
和你的机器一块沉河了
Drowned in the river with your machine.
胡说八道
That's nonsense.
蜘蛛侠试图阻止我研发聚变反应堆
Spider-Man was trying to stop my fusion reactor.
我制止了他
So I stopped him.
我掐住了他的喉咙...然后我...
I had him, by the throat.... And then, I...
我就到这里来了
And then I was here.
哦  拜托  听我说吧
Oh, please. Let me tell you something.
我当时把蜘蛛侠揍得屁滚尿流  不信你问他
I was whooping Spider-Man's ass. He'll tell you.
然后他造成了电力超载  我卡着动不了
And then he caused an overload. I was stuck in the grid,
一直在吸收能量  就要变成纯净能量体了  然后...
absorbing data. I was about to turn into pure energy, and then...
然后...哦  该死
And then... Oh, shit.
然后我就快死了
I was about to die.
麦克斯  你知道我死了吗
Max, do you know? Do I die?
-哦  太好了  你又抓到了一个   -等等
-Oh, great. You caught another one.   -No, wait.
斯特兰奇  他不是危险人物
Strange, he's not dangerous.
没关系
It's okay.
那是什么
What is that?
一件远古神器  科达莫斯方盒
It's an ancient relic. The Machinati Codamus.
把你搞错的咒语封印进去  一旦我做法完成
Trap your corrupted spell inside, once you finished the proper ritual,
它会逆转咒语  将那些人送回他们的宇宙
it will reverse the spell. And send these guys back to their universes.
然后呢  我们就死翘翘了
And then what? We perish?
别了吧  谢谢  我拒绝
Nah. No thanks, I'll pass on that.
让我出去  彼得
Let me out of here. Peter!
斯特兰奇...
Strange...
我们不能把他们送回去  至少现在还不行
We can't send them back. Not yet.
为什么
Why?
他们中有些人一回去就必死无疑
Some of these guys are gonna die.
帕克...
Parker...
这是他们的宿命
it's their fate.
拜托  斯特兰奇  有点同情心吧
Come on, Strange. Have a heart.
在多元宇宙宏大的运行中
In the grand calculus of the multiverse,
他们的牺牲比他们的生命重要得多
their sacrifice means infinitely more than their lives.
对不起  孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
他们死了就是死了
If they die, they die.
彼得
Peter!
别这样
Don't!
-兄弟  你在干什么   -彼得  你快走  快
-Dude, what are you doing?   -Peter, you gotta go. Go!
这就是我选择丁克的原因
This is why I never had kids.
-把盒子给我   -不
-Give me the box.   -No.
哇
Whoa!
天哪  我死了啊
Oh, my God. I'm dead.
你没死  只是灵魂出窍了
You're not dead. You've just been separated from your physical form.
出窍了...什么意思
My physical... What?!
-你是怎么做到的   -我不知道
-How are you doing that?   -I have no idea.
这不可能
You should not be able to do that.
这感觉绝了啊
This feels amazing.
这可能是我遇到过最酷的事情了
That might be one of the coolest things that's ever happened to me.
但仅此一次  下不为例
But don't ever do that again.
嘿  放开我
Hey. Get off of me!
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我掌控下的镜像空间
The Mirror Dimension. Where I'm in control.
斯特兰奇  住手  我们能不能谈一谈
Strange, stop. Can we please just talk about this?
帕克  你难道不知道吗  在多元宇宙中
Parker, don't you realize that in the multiverse,
有不计其数的人知道彼得·帕克就是蜘蛛侠
there are an infinite number of people who know Peter Parker is Spider-Man.
如果那个咒语出了问题  他们都会涌进这个宇宙的
And if that spell gets loose, they're all coming here.
我知道  我明白  但是我们不能让他们就这样回去送死
Look, I know. I get it. But we can't just send them home to die.
这是他们的宿命
It's their fate.
你无法改变这一点  正如你无法改变他们的身份
You can't change that anymore than you can change who they are.
如果我们可以改变他们的命运呢
But what if we could? What if we can change their fate?
你要干什么
What are you doing?
我不会还给你的...
I'm not giving you the...
还给我
Give me that back.
等等  那是阿基米德螺线吗
Wait a minute, is that an Archimedean spiral?
镜像空间居然是几何构造  你很擅长几何啊
The Mirror Dimension is just geometry? You're great at geometry.
几何题难不倒你啊
You can do geometry.
半径的平方除以曲线上的顶点数...
Square the radius, divided by, plot points along the curve...
好了  帕克  等结束后我再来接你
It's over, Parker. I'll come pick you up when it's done.
嘿  斯特兰奇  你知道比魔法更神奇的是什么吗
Hey, Strange. You know what's cooler than magic?
数学
Math.
别这样做
Don't do this.
噢
Oww.
对不起  先生  但是...
I'm sorry, sir, but...
我必须要试一试
I have to try.
兄弟  发生什么了
Dude, what happened?
我刚刚和奇异博士打了一架  我赢了
I just had a fight with Doctor Strange and I totally won!
-什么   -看  我还偷了他的戒指
-What?   -Look, and I stole his ring thing.
我本来荡着蛛丝飞过城市  然后就穿进了...
I was swinging through the city, and then I went through this...
一个巨大的镜像空间里
massive mirror thing,
-然后我又回到了城里了   -他人呢  他在哪
-and then I was back in the city.   -Where is he? Where is he?
他被困住了  但是...
He's trapped, but...
我不知道他会被困多久
I'm not sure for how long.
你本可以不管我们死活的
You could've just left us to die.
为什么要帮我们
Why didn't you?
因为见死不救  就不是他了
Because that's not who he is.
我应该可以帮助你们
I think I can help you guys.
如果我能治好你们  让你们恢复正常
If I can fix what happened to you,
等你们回去的时候  一切就会不一样了
then when you go back, things will be different
你们可能就不会死在与蜘蛛侠的战斗中
and you might not die fighting Spider-Man.
你说治好我们什么意思
What do you mean fix us?
-听着  我们的科技很先进   -我可以帮你
-Look, our technology is advanced...   -I can help you.
那个...我自己也是个科学家
You know, I'm something of a scientist myself.
奥克塔维斯了解我的能力
Octavius knows what I can do.
治好  你当我们是小狗吗
Fix? You mean like a dog?
我不要
I refuse.
我没办法向你们承诺什么
I can't promise you guys anything,
但至少这样你们就可以回到自己的时空  多次机会
but at least this way, you actually get to go home and have a chance.
改过自新的机会
A second chance.
想想看啊  难道不值得一试吗
I mean, come on. Isn't that worth trying?
相信我  彼得...
Trust me, Peter...
当你想改变别人
When you try to fix people,
就得承担得起后果
there are always consequences.
那你可以不来呀
I mean, you don't have to come.
我之前都不知道你还能说话呢
I also didn't know that you could talk.
但如果你们要留在这里
But if you stay here...
就得想办法对付那个巫师了
you're gonna have to deal with the wizard.
所以  我们要么跟你走要么死
So, we go along, or die.
基本上没得选啊  对吧
Not much of a choice, is it?
我只想回家
I just wanna go home.
我个人来讲的话  还不太想死
Well, I myself don't wanna be killed,
更别说死在一个奇装异服的人手里  所以...
especially by a guy dressed like Dungeons & Dragons, so...
你打算怎么办
What's your plan?
一切都在我的掌控之中
I have it all under control.
这玩意儿怎么办
What are we gonna do about this thing?
我们得找个地方好好保管它吧
Well, we need to find somewhere safe for it, right?
-对对对  -你拿去吧
-Yeah. Yes. Yes.   -You got to take it.
等等  啥
Wait, what?
如果出事了  我就给你发短信  你就按这个按钮
If something bad happens, I'll text you, and then you just push this
一切就结束了  他们都会消失
and then it's all over, and they'll all be gone.
我们要跟你一起去  我们不会丢下你一个人
We're going with you. We're not gonna leave you.
你们不能去  太危险了  你们做的已经够多了
You can't come with me. It's too dangerous. You guys have already done enough.
-彼得  我们要共进退   -我知道  内德
-Peter, we're in this together.   -I know we're in this together, Ned,
但我不能明知有危险还让你们去
but I can't do this if I know that you're in danger.
好吗  MJ  你拿着吧  就当是为了我
Okay? So for me, Mj please just take this.
求你了
Please.
-好吧   -谢谢你
-Fine.   -Thank you.
但是彼得  我发誓如果你失联了  我也会按下按钮的
But Peter, I swear, if I don't hear from you, I'm pressing the button.
-好   -那行  我说到做到哦
-Sure.   -Okay. And I will do it!
当然了  我们都相信你  米歇尔
Yeah, we all believe you, Michelle.
她不可能是他女朋友  不可能啊
No way that's his girlfriend. No way.
-她说到做到哦   -绝对的
-She'll do it.   -Absolutely. She will.
行吧
Okay.
一会儿见
See you later.
-注意安全   -你也是
-Be safe.   -You too.
哇
Whoa.
好吧
Okay.
-小心点   -好  你也是
-Be careful, okay?   -Yeah. You too.
所以...
So, uhh...
谁要一起来
Who's coming with me?
算我一个
Well, I'm in.
但是一旦有什么不对劲...
But, if this goes sideways...
我就给你电成烤蜘蛛
I'm gonna fry you from the inside out.
-康纳斯呢   -他跟我说想要留在卡车里
-Where's Connors?   -He told me he wants to stay in the truck.
-好吧   -警报系统已解除
-Okay.   -Alarm systems, deactivated.
梅姨
Aunt May.
-怎么了   -我觉得用哈皮的房子干这种事不太好
-Yeah.   -I feel kinda bad using Happy's place like this.
不会的  不会的  他不会在意的
No, no, no, no. He'll get over it.
不好意思
Sorry.
这就是你的计划吗  彼得
So this is your plan, Peter? Mmm?
实验室和设备你一个也没有  打算在公寓里创造奇迹呢
No lab, no facilities, just performing miracles in a condominium?
怎么  你打算用微波炉给我们熬制解药  再煎俩玉米饼吗
What, you're gonna cook up some cures, some frozen burritos in a microwave?
玉米饼不错啊  我可以来一个
I could go for a burrito.
他会把我们全害死的
He's gonna kill us all.
咱们往好处想吧
Well, let's hope not.
你是第一个  博士
You're up first, Doc.
什么  我跟你说了  我不需要治疗
What? Hey, I told you. I don't need fixing.
我不需要
I don't need fixing!
尤其不需要靠青少年  用单身狗的垃圾堆治疗我
Especially by a teenager using scraps from a bachelor's junk drawer.
不不不
No, no, no, no.
他还是有点东西的
He got something back there.
我能感觉到它
I can feel it.
一种奇怪的能量
Weird energy.
那是什么鬼东西啊
What the hell is that?
这是一个生成器
It's a fabricator.
基本上可以分析  设计  构建任何东西
It can analyze, design, construct basically anything.
我还以为那是个日光浴床  被哈皮睡塌了
I thought that was a tanning bed Happy broke.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
他肯定会把我们都害死
He's gonna kill us all.
博士脖子后面的芯片
So, the chip in the back of Doc's neck
是用来保护他的大脑
was designed to protect his brain from the A.I. system
不受人工智能系统控制触手的侵害  但你看这里...
that's controlling these tentacles. But if you look here...
芯片烧了  所以与其说他在控制触手
The chip is fried. So rather than him being in control of the tentacles,
不如说触手控制了他
the tentacles are now in control of him.
我想这解释了为什么...
Which, I guess explains why...
他总是很痛苦
he is so miserable all the time.
喝水吗
Thirsty?
嗯  喝点吧  我也渴了
Well, yes. I am thirsty.
白开水还是盐水
Fresh water or salt?
我想着  你不是叫章鱼吗
You know, because you're an octopus.
什么
What?
那就白开水吧
Fresh water it is.
瞧瞧这地方
Look at this place.
充满了可能性
And all the possibilities.
哪里  这个公寓吗
What? This condo?
对啊  这个公寓  我喜欢这样的开放式设计  不是
Yeah. yeah, the condo. I love the whole overfloor plan. No!
当然不是了  老哥  我说的是这个世界
No, man. I'm talking about the world.
我觉得现在的我挺好的
I kinda like who I am here.
如果有了里面那些能量加成
And all that power back there?
我能做的就更多了
I could be so much more.
你又为什么到这里来
So why did you come here?
我有个女儿
I have a daughter.
我还想见到她
And I wanna see her.
但在他完成他的科学小研究之前
But he's not gonna send anyone home.
谁都回不了家
Till he's finished his little science project back there.
-你相信他吗   -我不相信任何人
-You trust him?   -I don't trust anyone.
话说你怎么变成这样的
How'd you end up like that anyway?
我以前工作的地方
The place where I worked at...
他们在做电学实验
They were experimenting with electricity
利用活体生物产生的电能  然后...
created by living organisms, and then...
我掉进了一个全是电鳗的池子
I fell into a vat of electric eels.
真的假的
You're kidding.
-我掉进了一个超级粒子对撞机   -卧槽
-I fell into a supercollider.   -Damn.
看来咱摔倒的时候该小心点
Gotta be careful where you fall.
真了不起
Remarkable.
科技和你都很棒
The technology and you.
等这一切都结束了
When all this is over,
如果你愿意通勤
if you need a job and you're
来另一个宇宙找个班上...
willing to commute to another universe...
成功了  真的成了
It worked. That totally worked!
成功了  我做到了  我做好了
I got it. I did it. I did it.
-你能把他送上来吗   -这就来了
-Will you send him up?   -Yup. Here we go.
-冒犯了   -忍一下  博士
-Sorry.   -Hold on, Doc.
从我来之后就受尽羞辱
All of these humiliations never cease.
让你那科学博览会上的玩意离我远点
You! Keep your science fair project away from me!
嘿  会成功的  有点信心
Hey, it will work. Have faith.
你这个把自己变成怪物的智障还好意思说呢
Says the reckless fool who turned himself into a monster.
请不要乱动
Please stop. Hold still.
你敢碰我
Don't you dare.
我发誓  等我脱了身  我一定会...
I swear... when I get out of this wicker, I'm gonna...
博士
Doc?
奥克塔维斯博士
Doctor Octavius?
好安静...
It's so quiet...
盘旋在我脑海里的
Those voices...
那些声音...
Inside my head...
我几乎都要忘了...
I'd almost forgotten...
奥托
Otto.
我在
Yes.
诺曼
Norman.
是我
It's me.
谁敢相信啊
Would you look at that.
我很感激你  好孩子  真的
I'm grateful, dear boy. Truly.
没事  不用客气
Yeah. You're welcome.
我能帮你做点什么
How can I help you?
我是彼得  请留言
This is Peter. Leave a message.
嗨  彼得  我是哈皮  我看了看我家门口的监控
Yeah, Peter, this is Happy. I accessed my doorbell camera...
那些家伙都是谁啊
Who are those guys, huh?
那是个生化人吗  你带了个有机械触手的生化人来我家
Is that a cyborg, you bring a cyborg with robot legs into my house?
还有个人身上糊满泥巴  怎么回事啊  速速回电
One of the guys was made of mud? What's going on? Call me back.
诺曼  你感觉怎么样
How does it feel, Norman?
你即将成为完整的人了
You're about to become whole again.
不再有邪恶的黑暗面了
No more darker half.
只有完完整整的你自己
Just you.
只有我
Just me.
好吧  嗯...
Okay. Umm...
就放在这里  这个东西...
It just goes right here, this one...
现在应该正在吸收你体内的能量
That should be drawing power now.
我一会儿就来检查  但是...
I'm gonna come back in a second just to check on it, but...
看着点指示灯  都变绿的话
Keep an eye on the lights. When they're all green,
就代表你体内的电全部耗尽了
it means all the electricity in your body's dissipated.
嗯  不是所有的电啦
Well, not all the electricity.
我是说  当然你的大脑需要电流来正常运作...
I mean, obviously you know you need electricity for your brain to function...
你的神经系统也是...
Your nervous system is...
我也不知道为什么要和你解释身体里的电
I'm not really sure why I'm explaining electricity to you.
-我能问你一个问题吗   -当然
-Can I ask you a question?   -Sure.
这些是你的乐高玩具吗
Are these your legos?
呃  我该走了
I gotta go.
一会就回来
I'll be back.
-感觉有点不对劲   -怎么了
-Something feels off.   -What do you mean?
-我不喜欢这样   -别管它了
-I don't like this.   -Leave it alone.
你们越快解决问题  我们就能越早回家
The sooner you guys get through with this, the sooner we go home.
-怎么样  他在哪呢   -他在里面
-Well? Where is he?   -He's inside.
那我们怎么在外面
And yet here we are outside.
我不是说了吗  别跟丢了
Did you not hear me say don't lose him?
我需要蜘蛛侠的清晰影像
I want incriminating footage of Spider-Man.
我已经通知了灾害控制局  他们马上到
I already called Damage Control. They are on their way.
好戏开场了
And so it begins.
彼得
Peter?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道
I don't know.
梅姨
May?
发生什么了  彼得
What is it, Peter?
怎么了  彼得
What's up, Peter?
你为什么用那种表情看我
Why are you looking at me like that?
你的蜘蛛第六感  还真是个巧妙的小把戏
That's some neat trick. That sense of yours.
诺曼
Norman?
诺曼不在呢  亲爱的
Norman's on sabbatical, honey.
什么鬼
The hell?
是绿魔
Goblin.
再也没有邪恶的黑暗面  你真以为我会允许这种事发生吗
No more darker half? Did you really think that I'd let that happen?
只因为你不知道真正的力量能带给你什么
That I'd let you take away my power just because
我就会让你夺走我的能力吗
you're blind to what true power can bring you?
-你根本就不了解我   -是吗
-You don't know me.   -Don't I?
我看到她是怎么困住你的
I saw how she trapped you.
为了她所谓神圣的道德使命而战
Fighting her holy moral mission.
我们根本不需要你来拯救
We don't need you to save us.
我们无需治疗
We don't need to be fixed.
这些不是诅咒
These are not curses.
它们是上天的馈赠
They're gifts.
不要  诺曼
Norman, no.
-闭嘴  哈巴狗   -你不知道你在说什么
-Quiet, lapdog.   -You don't know what you're talking about.
我一直通过诺曼懦弱的双眼观察你
I watched you from deep behind Norman's cowardly eyes.
你为自己想要的一切苦苦挣扎
Struggling, to have everything you want,
但这个世界却逼迫你做出选择
while the world tries to make you choose.
然而神无需选择
Gods don't have to choose.
我们只需索取
We take.
梅  快跑
May, run!
上帝啊  你都干了什么好事
Oh, my God. What have you done?
我还是更喜欢以前的你
I liked you better before.
上面  他在上面  就是之前桥上那家伙
Up here! He's up there. It's the guy from the bridge.
是我眼花了吗
Did you see that?
下去吧你
Get off me!
徒有强大能力...
Strong enough to have it all...
却懦弱得不敢索取
Too weak to take it!
我可算抓到你了
Now I've gotcha.
我早说过这样做你要承担后果的
I told you there'd be consequences!
你的弱点  彼得...
Your weakness, Peter...
就是你的道德感
is morality.
它会扼住你的喉咙
It's choking you.
感觉到了吗
Can you feel it?
没用的
It didn't work.
诺曼说得对
Norman was right.
是你传给他的  可悲的懦夫
He got it from you. That pathetic sickness!
你想治好我...
You tried to fix me...
梅姨  快走...
May, go...
现在  换我来修理你
Now, I'm gonna fix you.
梅姨  快跑  求你了...
May, run, please...
梅姨
May!
彼得  彼得  彼得...
Peter, Peter, Peter...
善心总有恶报
No good deed goes unpunished.
不用着急谢我
You can thank me later.
不要
No!
-梅姨   -彼得...
-May?   -Peter...
梅姨  梅姨...我在这呢
May, May... I'm here.
我在这
I'm here.
-你还好吗   -嗯嗯  嗯嗯
-Are you okay?   -Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
真没事吗
Really?
是啊
Yeah.
-没事的  我们没事了对吗   -没事了
-It's okay. We're okay, right?   -Yeah.
我磕到了头
Knocked off my head.
-我也是   -其他没事
-Yeah, me too.   -That's all.
我觉得我肋骨折了
I think I broke my ribs.
都怪我啊  梅
This is all my fault, May.
-不是的   -我应该听斯特兰奇的
-No.   -I should've just listened to Strange
-让他把他们送回去   -你做得对
-and let him send them back...   -You did the right thing.
不然他们会死掉的
They would have been killed.
你做得对
You did the right thing.
那份责任不属于我  梅姨
It's not my responsibility, May.
诺曼怎么说的来着
What Norman said?
我的道德使命
My moral mission.
-不  彼得  听着  你听我说   -不  梅姨 你别...
-No, Peter. Listen. You listen to me.   -No, May, you don't have...
你拥有这份能力
You have a gift.
你拥有力量
You have power.
能力越大  责任越大
And with great power, there must also come great responsibility.
是啊  我明白
Yeah. I know.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
好  我们走
Okay, let's go.
-怎么了  你还好吗   -嗯  没事
-What happened? Are you okay?  -Yeah okay.
没事就好  这是怎么了
Yeah, you're okay. What happened?
就等一会儿...我喘口气
Just one second... to catch my breath...
好啊  你喘口气  我就在这呢
Okay. Well, catch your breath. I'm right here.
我们慢慢来  你喘口气  然后...
We're gonna take our time, you catch your breath, and...
然后我们送你去医院  好吗
and we'll take you to a Doctor, okay?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
有人来帮帮忙吗  这里要叫救护车
Somebody help. I need an ambulance.
救命  有没有人...
Please, somebody...
怎么了
What happened?
没事  你没事的  你没事的
Nothing. You're okay. You're okay.
我就是...喘口气
I'll just... catch my breath...
好  我就在这里  我就在这里
Okay. I'm right here. I'm right here.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
我们不会有事的
We're okay.
就我和你
Just me and you.
梅姨
May?
你能看看我吗  梅姨  求你了
Will you look at me, May? Please?
梅姨  梅姨
May? May?
你在干什么呢  梅姨  求你了
What are you doing, May? Please,
你能不能起来和我说句话  求求你
will you just wake up and talk to me, please?
下车  快点
Get out of the car now! Move!
过来  过来  过来
Get down.  Get down. Get down.
彼得  快跑啊
Peter! Run!
你没事的  就我和你
You are okay. It's just me and you.
对不起  真的对不起
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
好了  帕克  举起手  走出来
Alright, Parker. Come out with your hands up.
立刻出来  不然我们开火了
Come out right now. Or we will open fire.
快跑
Run!
一场悲剧
Tragedy.
不然我还能怎么形容呢
What else can I call it?
还需要多言什么
What more need be said?
断壁残垣...
The damage...
满目疮痍...
The destruction...
大家都亲眼目睹
You saw it with your own eyes.
人们何时才能醒悟
When will people wake up, and realize
蜘蛛侠所到之处
that everywhere Spider-Man goes...
混乱与灾难接踵而至
Chaos and calamity ensue.
蜘蛛侠所及之物皆会毁灭
Everything Spider-Man touches comes to ruin.
而我们这些无辜民众
And we, the innocents,
要留下来收拾残局
are left to pick up the pieces.
J·乔纳·詹姆斯为您报道
J. Jonah Jameson, reporting.
晚安
Good night.
愿上帝保佑我们
And God help us all.
还是没消息吗
Still nothing?
没
No.
我要按了
I'm gonna press it.
-什么  不行   -彼得让我等他  但...
-What? No!   -Peter told me to wait, but...
我要按了
I'm gonna do it.
我只希望...我只希望我们能见到他
I just wish... I just wish that we could see him.
-内德   -什么
-Ned?   -Yeah?
-再来一次   -好
-Do that again.   -Yeah.
我只希望我们能见到他
I just wish we could see him.
好吧...
Okay...
我只希望我们能见到彼得
I just wish we could see Peter.
魔法师
Salamangkero!
您说的没错  我会魔法
You're right. I am magic.
是他吗
Is that him?
-那当然了  不是他还能是谁   -彼得
-Yeah, yeah. It has to be.   -Peter.
-彼得  彼得   -嘿  彼得
-Peter. Peter!   -Hey, Peter!
彼得
Peter!
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi!
不  不  别紧张  我可是好人
No, no, no. It's okay, it's okay. I'm nice guy.
好吧
Okay...
你特么是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是彼得·帕克
I'm Peter Parker.
别逗了行吗
That's not possible.
我是蜘蛛侠
I am Spider-Man.
在我的那个世界里  但是  好像是昨天
In my world. But then, yesterday?
我就...
I was...
我就直接来到了这个世界
I was just here.
不可思议
Wow.
弦理论...
String theory...
多重现实...
Multidimensional reality...
还有物质位移
And matter displacement.
都是真的吗
All real?
对啊...
Yeah...
我就知道
Knew it!
应该是我的咒语出了问题
This has to be because of the spell.
咒语
The spell?
-是那种魔法咒语吗   -不是咒语你听错了
-Like magic spell?   -There's no spell.
-没这回事   -没有
-No spell.   -No.
魔法在这里也真实存在吗
Magic's real here, too?
-就是说...   -闭嘴  内德
-I mean...   -Shut up, Ned.
-不是真实存在的啦  -快闭嘴
-No, it's not real.   -Shut up.
我是说...这里是有魔术师之类的东西啦  但可没有...
I mean... There's magicians and stuff, but there's no like...
闭嘴行吗  闭嘴
Stop it. Stop.
-证明一下   -证明啥
-Prove it.   -Prove what?
证明你是彼得·帕克
That you're Peter Parker.
我一般不随身携带身份证的  懂我意思吗
I don't carry an ID with me, you know?
有点不符合匿名超英的作风
Kinda defeats the whole anonymous superhero thing?
-你干嘛呢   -我看看你有没有那个一激灵
-Why'd you do that?   -To see if you have the tingle thing.
我有倒是有  只不过对面包不起效
I have the tingle thing, just not from bread.
你能别朝我扔面包了吗
Can you not throw the bread again?
你很难信任别人
You're a deeply mistrusting person.
我理解
And I respect that.
爬一圈
Crawl around.
-爬一圈吗   -没错
-Crawl around?   -Yes.
-我不   -你必须爬
-No.   -Yes. Crawl around.
-我到底为什么要爬一圈啊   -因为你现在这样还不够证明
-Why do I need to crawl around?   -Cause it's not enough.
-已经够了   -根本不够
-This is plenty.   -No, it's not.
-我这样已经够意思了   -我说不够  还不够
-Yes, it is.   -No, it's not. Nuh-uh.
我就问你我是靠什么黏住天花板的
How do I stick to the ceiling?
快点
Do it.
内德...
Ned...
帮我跟那个人说
sabihin mo diyan sa mamang yan,
能不能把那边的蛛网弄掉
na alisin yung agiw sa sulok. Ha?
我奶奶问你能不能把那边的蜘蛛网清理一下
My Lola's asking if you could just get the cobweb there.
-太高了...  我们够不到   -好
-It's too, like, up there?   -Yeah.
感谢你
Thank you.
可以了吧
We're good?
相信我了吧
We're good.
暂时吧
For now.
我开错了传送门  然后带来了错误的彼得·帕克
So, I opened a wrong portal to the wrong Peter Parker.
确实  你就继续试吧  直到找到真的那个
Yeah, I guess you just keep doing it until you find the real one.
-扎心了   -无意冒犯
-Ouch.   -No offense.
-好吧   -没事  你可以的
-Okay.   -Okay. You got it.
找到彼得·帕克
Find Peter Parker.
他手上这东西是什么
What's this thing on his hand?
找到彼得·帕克
Find Peter Parker.
Find Peter Parker!
好家伙  找到了个路人甲
Great, it's just some random guy.
你们好啊
Hello.
应该没什么事吧  我直接穿过了这个...
I hope it's okay, I just came through this...
它又关上了
It just closed.
你是彼得吗
You're Peter?
对  彼得·帕克
Yeah. Peter Parker.
诶...我好像看到过你们俩...
I... I've seen you two...
你好啊
Hi.
等等  他...他好像不是你们那个朋友啊
Wait. He's... He's not your friend...
就是说  你也是蜘蛛侠咯
Whoa, it's... So you're Spider-Man too?
你怎么不直接告诉我们呢
Why didn't you just say that?
我还真不会大张旗鼓地宣传这个
I generally don't go around advertising it.
有点不符合匿名超英的作风
Kinda defeats the whole anonymous superhero thing.
-和我刚才说的一样   -和他刚才说的一样
-I just said that...   -That's what he just said.
你啊  赶紧动起来
Ikaw, ha? Nagkalat ka nanaman.
把你造出来的垃圾都打扫干净
Linisin mo lahat ng mga basura mo dito.
还有你  我很想让我们的屋子干干净净的
At ikaw? Alam mo na gusto ko itong bahay natin, maayos.
但是你看这也脏了  那也脏了
pero tingnan mo, dumi dito, dumi doon.
我奶奶想问  你们能不能把你们刚刚弄的蛛网清理干净
My Lola's asking if you could clean up the webs that you just shot.
-哦  抱歉  奶奶  -我们会清理掉的
-Oh. Sorry, Lola.   -Yes, of course.
我睡觉去了
I'm going to bed.
-晚安  奶奶   -晚安  内德奶奶
-Night, Lola.   -Good night, Ned's Lola.
说起来可能有点奇怪  但是...
This might seem kind of weird, but...
自从我来到这里之后  我就一直在找你们的朋友
I've been trying to find your friend ever since I got here.
我有一种感觉...
I just had this sense that...
他需要我的帮助
That he needs my help.
我们的帮助
Our help.
他确实需要
He does.
-可是我们不知道他在哪   -而且  嗯...
-We don't know where he is.   -And, umm...
说实话  他现在只有我们了
Honestly, right now, we're all he really has left.
这样吧  有没有这样一些地方
Well, is there some place,
对他来说意义非凡  他可能会去的
that he might go that has meaning to him?
像那种...
Like a...
他在那里可以直接...
a place where he would go to just...
逃离一切吗
Get away from everything?
是我的话  我会去克莱斯勒大厦楼顶
For me, it was the top of the Chrysler Building.
我去的是帝国大厦
Empire State.
视野更好
Better view.
那儿确实风景好
That is a sweet view.
有的
Yes.
对的  我想我知道他会去哪
Yeah, I think I know exactly where that would be.
对不起
I'm sorry.
彼得  有...还有别人来了
Peter,there's some... there's some people here...
什么  是谁
What? Who?
嘿  等下  等下
Hey. Wait, wait, whoa.
我很抱歉...
Sorry...
梅姨的事
About May.
节哀
Yeah. Sorry.
-我差不多理解你正在经历什么...   -不不不
-I got some understanding of what you're going through...   -No no no.
别说的你很了解我一样
Please don't tell me that you know what I'm going through.
好
Okay.
她死了
She's gone.
都怪我
It's all my fault.
让她白白送命
She died for nothing.
所以我一开始就该这么做
So I'm gonna do what I should've done in the first place.
-彼得...   -不用说了
-Peter...   -Please, don't.
你们俩都不属于这里  所以我要送你们回家了
You don't belong here. Either of you, so I'm sending you home.
那些家伙都是来自你们的世界  对吧
Those other guys are from your worlds, right?
那就留给你们处置吧
So you deal with it.
如果他们死了  或是你们杀了他们...
If they die, if you kill them...
那都是算在你们头上的
That's on you.
不关我事
It's not my problem.
我什么都不在乎了
I don't care anymore.
我受够了
I'm done.
很抱歉把你们都卷了进来
I'm really sorry that I dragged you into this.
但你们现在得回去了
But you have to go home now.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
我的本叔叔被杀了
My Uncle Ben was killed.
是我的错
It was my fault.
我失去了...
I lost...
我失去了格温  她是我的...
I lost Gwen. My...
她就是我的MJ
She was my MJ.
我没能救下她
I couldn't save her.
我永远都不会原谅我自己
I'm never gonna be able to forgive myself for that.
但我坚持了下去  试着...
But I carried on. Tried to...
试着继续  继续去做那个...
Tried to keep going. Tried to keep being the...
...大家的友好邻居蜘蛛侠  因为
... friendly neighborhood Spider-Man, because
我知道她也希望我这么做  但是...
I know that's what she would have wanted. But...
有些时候  我就...
At some point, I just...
下手毫不留情
I stopped pulling my punches.
我变得愤恨
I got rageful.
充满怒火
I got bitter.
我只是不想让你也变得...和我一样
I just don't want you, to end up like... Like me.
本叔叔去世的那晚
The night Ben died,
我抓到了我以为的凶手
I hunted down the man who I thought did it.
我恨不得杀了他
I wanted him dead.
虽然我得偿所愿了
I got what I wanted.
但我并没觉得更好受
It didn't make it better.
我花了很久一段时间...
It took me a long time to...
学习如何熬过这些黑暗的日子
learn to get through that darkness.
我就是想杀了他
I wanna kill him.
把他四分五裂
I wanna tear him apart.
梅姨的声音还回荡在我的脑海中
I can still hear her voice in my head.
尽管她身受重伤  她还告诉我  我们做得对
Even after she was hurt, she said to me that we did the right thing.
她跟我说  能力越大...
She told me that with great power...
责任越大
comes great responsibility.
等下  你怎么知道这句话
Wait, what? How do you know that?
本叔叔告诉我的
Uncle Ben said it.
就在他去世的那天
The day he died.
也许她并没有白白送命  彼得
Maybe she didn't die for nothing, Peter.
好吧  那么...
Okay, so...
康纳斯  马尔科  狄龙  还有...
Connors, Marko, Dillon, and...
听着  我大概能修好狄龙和马尔科的装置  但其他人的...
Look, I think that I can repair the devices for Dillon and Marko, but the others...
我能搞定康纳斯的  毕竟我已经治好他一次了  小事一桩
Well, I got Connors. I've already cured him once, so no big deal.
咋了  就是小事一桩啊
What? It's no big deal.
赞
Great.
是啊  赞
Yeah. That's great.
我觉得我能给奥斯本博士做一份抗血清
I think I can make an antiserum for Doctor Osborn.
我已经想了很久了
Been thinking about it a long time.
我们得把他们全治好
Gotta cure all of them.
好吗
Right?
好
Right.
我们就是干这个的
That's what we do.
咋了
What?
这有三个你
It's three yous.
所以说...
So...
你也有好基友吗
Do you have a best friend too?
曾经有过
I did.
什么叫曾经有过
You did?
他想杀了我来着
He died in my arms.
然后死在了我怀里
After he tried to kill me.
真是心碎呢
It was heartbreaking.
我滴天
Dude.
你能...帮我跑个检测吗
Will you...run a diagnostic?
好的
Okay.
嘿  你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
嗯还好  你呢
Yeah, I'm fine. You okay?
你不该承受这些的
You don't deserve this.
-我毁了你的人生...   -嘿别这么说
-I ruined your life...   -Hey. No, no, no, no, no.
看着我  我就在这儿呢
Look at me. I'm here.
我哪儿都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我们会挺过去的  我们会一起度过难关的
We're gonna get through this. We're gonna get through it together.
好吗
Okay?
好的
Okay.
你现在有另一半吗
You have someone?
没有
No.
我没时间过彼得·帕克自己的生活...你懂吧
I got no time for Peter Parker stuff... You know?
你有吗
Do you?
呃  我的情况有点...复杂
It's a little... complicated.
我知道  我懂
I understand.
我猜像我们这样的人都是情路坎坷的
I guess it's just not in the cards for guys like us.
嗯...
Well...
可我没有放弃
I wouldn't give up.
花了一段时间  但是...
Took a while, but...
-我们想出了办法   -是吗
-We made it work.   -Yeah?
是啊  我和...
Yeah. Me and...
MJ
MJ.
我的MJ  她...
My MJ. She, uhh...
在这里容易混淆啊  是吧
It gets confusing, huh?
彼得
Peter?
在  不好意思  你是叫...那位  还是...
Yeah? Oh, sorry. You mean...that or...?
我叫彼得  彼得
Peter-Peter.
-我们都叫彼得  内德   -是的  内德  我们都是彼得
-We're all called Peter, Ned.   -Yeah. Peter, Ned. Peter
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker?
-还是一样   -我们都是彼得·帕克
-Same again.   -We're all Peter Parker.
-电脑   -哦
-The computer!   -Oh.
-哦  我的准备好了   -我也是
-Oh, I'm ready.   -Yeah, me too.
好的  现在我们只需要把这些家伙引到一个地方  对吧
Okay, so... Now, all we gotta do is lure these guys someplace, right?
在他们试图杀我们的时候  治好他们  然后送他们回家
Try to cure them, while they try to kill us, and then, send them home.
用一个魔法盒子
Using a magic box?
是的  计划就是这样
Well, that's the plan.
那么你是要打扮成一个酷酷的青年牧师去参战呢
So are you gonna go into battle dressed as a cool, youth pastor,
还是你也有战衣
or do you got your suit?
好极了
Good.
这是你的蛛丝盒
Here's your web cartridges.
哦  谢了内德
Oh, thanks, Ned.
这玩意是干啥的
What's that for?
是我的蛛丝液  放在我的蛛丝发射器里  怎么了
It's my web fluid. It's for my web shooters. Why?
-你直接从体内射出蛛丝吗   -是啊
-That came out of you?   -Yeah.
-你不行吗   -不行啊
-You can't do that, huh?   -No.
你到底是怎么做到...
How on Earth is that...
总之  我们跑题了  看
Anyway, we're getting sidetracked. Look,
我们在这个地方动手  这里被围起来了
this is where we're gonna do this, okay? It's isolated,
所以不会伤及别人
so no one should get hurt.
我们用盒子把他们引过去  他们都想要那盒子
We draw them there with the box, it's the one thing they all want.
我们只要想好怎么过去
All we have to do is figure out how we're gonna get there.
哦  我们可以开传送门过去
Oh, we can portal there.
-什么   -我现在会魔法的
-What?   -I magic now.
是  是真的  他确实会
Yeah, no, no. He's right. He can. He can.
-是的  我们看见了   -确实
-Yeah, we saw him.   -Yeah. He is.
-等等  认真的吗   -哥们  我现在会奇异博士的魔法了
-Wait, really?   -Dude, I got Doctor Strange magic.
-真的假的   -没错是真的
-What?   -Yeah!
还有  我向你保证...
And I promise you...
我不会变成大反派来杀你的
I won't turn into a supervillain and try to kill you.
好吧...
Okay...
非常感谢
Thank you.
嗯...
Umm...
好了  别管那么多了  你常说的那句话是什么
Alright. Here goes nothing. What's that thing you always say?
-如果你做好会失望的准备...   -不  不
-If you expect disappointment...   -No, no, no...
我们去揍他们个落花流水
We gotta kick some ass.
好的
Okay.
是治
Cure.
好好治治他们
Cure some ass.
治他丫的
Cure that ass.
女士们  先生们...
Ladies and gentlemen...
号角热线接到了电话  正是逃犯蜘蛛侠打来的
The Bugle tip line has just received a call from none other than the fugitive known as Spider-Man.
他刚在皇后区大闹了一场
Fresh from his rampage in Queens.
彼得·帕克  你又打算宣扬什么有害的想法
So, Peter Parker... What pernicious propaganda are you peddling?
-只想说真相而已   -哦  当然
-Just the truth.   -Oh, sure.
真相就是...
Truth is...
这全都是我的错
That this is all my fault.
我不小心把那几个危险的坏人带到了这里
I accidentally brought those dangerous people here.
嗯  他居然承认了
Well, he admits it!
如果那几个人在看节目的话...
And if those people are watching...
我做的一切都是为了帮你们
Just know that I really did try to help you.
我本可以杀了你们
I could've killed you.
随时都可以  但我没有
At any given moment, but I didn't.
因为我的梅姨教导我  每个人都应该有个改过自新的机会
Because my Aunt May taught me that everyone deserves a second chance.
因此我在这里
And that's why I'm here.
这里是指哪里  说具体点
And where is here, exactly?
最能代表改过自新机会的地方
A place that represents second chances.
自由女神像吗  我的天呐  家人们
The Statue of Liberty? Good God, folks!
他要摧毁另一个国家地标建筑了
He's about to destroy another national landmark.
全世界的观众朋友们  如果你们在看...
The world, if you're watching...
相信我  大家肯定都在看
Believe me, the world is watching.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
你们的友好邻居蜘蛛侠真的需要些好运
Your friendly neighborhood Spider-Man could really use some.
好嘞  兄弟们  他们随时会来
Okay, guys. It could be any minute now.
好的  快完事了
Yup. Almost done.
你们知道吗  麦克斯是我见过的最贴心的人
You know, Max was like,the sweetest guy ever.
直到他掉进了...
Before he fell into a...
一个养电鳗的池子
pool of electric eels.
怪不得啊
That'll do it.
又来了...
There it goes...
-你还好吗   -哦
-You okay?   -Oops
我的背
My back.
我估计可能是荡来荡去太多了  有点僵
It's kind of stiff from all the swinging, I guess.
哦对没错  我腰中间也疼
Oh, yeah, no, I got a middle back pain, too.
-真的吗   -真的
-Really?   -Yeah.
想让我帮你拉伸下吗
You want me to crack it?
好啊
Yeah.
那太棒了
That would be great.
-你准备好了吗   -好了
-You ready?   -Yeah.
太带劲儿了
That's good.
感觉怎么样
How is it?
爽啊
Wow.
-挺不错的   -对吧
-That's good.   -Right?
-感觉好多了   -那就行
-That's better.   -Yeah.
太爽了
Wow.
我天  这太酷了
God, this is so cool.
我一直都想有几个兄弟的
I always wanted brothers.
所以你自身能够制造蛛丝吗
So you could like make your own web fluid in your body?
咱们还是别聊这个话题了
I'd rather not talk about this.
不  我并不是想...
No, I don't mean to...
-你在嘲讽我吗   -不不不  当然不是了
-Are you teasing me?   -No, no, no. No, no, no.
他没有嘲讽你  只是...
He's not teasing you. It's just that...
我们都做不到  所以自然好奇你的蛛丝是什么情况
We can't do that, so naturally we're curious as to how your web situation works.
-就是这样   -如果涉及到你的个人隐私  那我就不多问了
-That's all.   -If it's personal, I don't wanna...like pry.
-我只是觉得你这样很酷   -不
-I just think it's cool.   -No.
我也想告诉你们  但我没办法解释  这就好比...
I wish I could tell you, but it's like, I don't do it... Like I don't...
-好比我不刻意呼吸  呼吸自然发生   -哇哦
-Like, I don't do breathing. Like, breathing just happens.   -Whoa.
所以只有你的手腕能射出蛛丝  还是...
Like, does it just come out of your wrists, or...
其他地方也能射出来
Does it come out off anywhere else?
只有... 只有手腕啦
Only... only the wrists.
你从来没有射不出蛛丝的时候吗  我的蛛丝总是不够用
You never had to web block? Cause I run out of webs all the time.
我不得不自己搞了个实验室做蛛丝
I had to make my own lab.
可麻烦了呢
And it's a hassle.
是啊  听起来确实很麻烦
That sounds like a hassle. Yeah.
但你这么一说  我也有过这种情况  我那个时候...
But I did, actually, as you said that. I was like...
-也射不出蛛丝   -为什么啊
-I had a web block.   -Why?
怀疑自我价值之类的事儿
Existential crisis stuff.
-哎  快别提了   -嘿...
-Yeah, don't get me started on that.   -Hey...
你们有打过什么超疯狂的反派吗
What are like, some of the craziest villains that you guys have fought?
看来你已经见过几位了
Seems you've met some of them.
-这问题问得好   -我之前打过一个...
-That's a good question.   -I fought a...
一个外星人...
an alien...
-由黑色粘液构成的外星人   -巧了啊
-made out of black goo once.   -No way!
我也和外星人打过
I fought an alien, too.
-在地球上和外太空都打过   -哇
-On Earth and in space.   -Oh
-是的  他还是紫色的呢   -我也想打一打外星人
-Yeah. He was purple.   -I wanna fight an alien.
我还是很惊讶...
I'm, I'm still, like...
你竟然在太空里打过外星人
That you fought an alien, in Space.
和你们一比我好菜  我只打过一个俄罗斯人...
I'm lame compare to... like, I fought a Russian guy in a...
他操纵着一个犀牛形机器
Like a rhinoceros machine.
等等  咱们倒回到之前你说你好菜
Hey, can we rewind it back to the "I'm lame" part?
-因为你一点都不菜   -谢谢
-'Cause, you are not.   -Aw, thanks.
不  好吧  谢了  我不是说我菜
No, yeah. I appreciate it, I'm not saying I'm lame.
但这是一种自我暗示  或许我们应该...
But it's just the self-talk maybe we should, you know...
是的  听着...
Yeah, listen...
你...你很超凡
You're... You're Amazing.
你好好想一想
Just to take it in for a minute.
-行行行  我想下   -你...很超凡
-Yeah, yeah, yeah I can take it.  I can take it.  -You... You are amazing.
-我知道啦   -你最棒啦
-I can take that.   -You are amazing.
-谢谢你   -你能自己说出来嘛
-Thank you. Yeah. Thank you.   -Will you say it?
不了  我听到有人这么跟我说就行了  谢谢
No, I kinda needed to hear that. Thank you.
好了  各位  集中精神
Alright guys, focus up.
-你们感觉到了吗   -感觉到了
-Can you feel that?   -Yeah.
你好啊  彼得
What's up, Peter?
你觉得我的新造型咋样
How do you like the new new?
听着  把东西给我  我要毁了它
Look, you give it to me, I'm gonna destroy it.
但我会给你留个活口
But I'll let you live.
别逼我杀人  彼得
Don't make me a murderer, Peter.
好了  各位  准备就绪
Okay, guys. Here it comes.
嘿  麦克斯
Hey, Max!
许久不见  甚是想念啊  兄弟
I missed you, man!
好了  MJ  接好
All right, MJ, heads up!
接住了  快把门关上
Got it! Close it.
-内德  没关上啊   -嗯  我知道
-Ned, it's not closing   -Yeah, I know.
为啥关不上啊
Why isn't it closing?
-我也不知道...我...   -你之前关上过吗
-I don't know... I...   -Did you close before. Did you...
-没有吗   -没有啊  我只开过几个
-No?   -No. I mean I have opened some.
麦克斯  麦克斯  我们能谈谈吗  就咱们俩人  就...
Max, Max, Max. Can we just talk for a second? Just you and me, just...
看看是谁来了  是我的老朋友蜘蛛侠啊
Look who showed up! My old friend Spider-Man.
我是在救你  麦克斯  我只想救你
I'm trying to save you, Max. That's all I've ever wanted.
-你才不是想救我呢   -我认真的
-You're not trying to save me.   -I am.
你现在毛都算不上
You ain't even a shit no more.
别瞎担心我了  我能救我自己
Don't worry about me. I'll save myself.
我已经跟他交上手了  现在呢
I got his attention, now what?
好的好的
Ok great.
就是说下  蜥蜴人也来了
Just FYI, Lizard-guy is here too.
兄弟们  通讯还顺畅吗  你们在吗
Guys, comm check, hello.
给我麦克斯的解药
I need Max's cure.
好的  我来了
Yeah. I'm on it.
彼得  给我蜥蜴的解药
Peter! I need the Lizard cure.
好的  好的
Okay! Okay!
那盒子在哪儿  彼得
Where's the box, Peter?
-弗林特  我们可以帮助所有人   -我才不在乎
-Flint! We can help everyone.   -I don't care!
抱歉
Sorry!
啊好恶心
Gross.
我告诉过你了  沙人  谁都回不了家
I tried to tell you, Sandman. Nobody's going home.
刚才什么鬼啊
What the hell is going on out there?
我一直在喊你  彼得二号  彼得二号...
I kept yelling at you, Peter 2, Peter 2...
-我知道  但我以为你是彼得二号呢   -什么
-I know, but I thought you're Peter 2?   -What?
-我才不是彼得...   -你俩都别吵了  听彼得一号讲
-I'm not Peter...   -Stop arguing, both of you! Listen to Peter 1.
-听着  显然我们不太合拍   -是的
-Look, we're clearly not very good at this!   -Yeah.
我知道  我知道  我们太差劲了
I know, I know. We suck.
我...我不知道怎样团队合作
I, I don't know how to work as a team.
-我也不懂   -我懂
-Me neither.   -Well I do.
我之前参加过一个团队  好吗
I have been in a team, okay?
我不想吹牛哈  但我要说了
I don't wanna brag, but I will.
-我加入过复仇者联盟   -复仇者联盟
-I was in the Avengers.   -The Avengers?
-是的   -太棒了啊
-Yeah.   -That's great!
-谢谢   -那是什么啊
-Thank you.   -What is that?
等等  你们那里没有复仇者联盟吗
Wait, you don't have the Avengers?
是乐队吗  你加入过乐队
Is that a band? Are you in a band?
不  不是乐队  复仇者联盟是...
No, I'm not in a band. No, the Avengers is a...
-地球上最强大的...   -说这有用吗
-Earth's Mightiest...   -How is this helping?!
不重要了  我们只需要集中注意力  相信你们的蜘蛛第六感
Look, it's not important. All we gotta do is focus, trust your tingle,
-互相配合进攻  好吗   -好的
-and coordinate our attacks, okay?   -Yes.
-好  我们选定一个目标   -没错
-Okay. Let's pick one target.   -Right.
将他们逐个击败
We take them off the board one at a time.
你开窍了  好的
Now you got it. Okay...
-我是彼得一号  那你是彼得二号...   -彼得二号
-Peter 1, Peter 2...   -Peter 2.
-你是彼得三号   -彼得三号
-Peter 3.   -Peter 3!
-好  那咱们上吧...   -不  等一下  等一下
-All right, let's do this...    -No, wait, wait, wait, wait!
我爱你们
I love you guys.
谢谢
Thank you.
-好  一起上吧    -走吧
-All right. Let's do this.   -Let's go.
好的  蜘蛛侠们
Okay, Spider-Man.
先把沙人解决了
Sandman first.
我来把他带到雕像里
I'm gonna lead himinside the statue.
我们顶上见
I'll meet you at the top.
-嘿  康纳斯博士   -你好啊  彼得
-Hey, Dr. Connors.   -Hello, Peter.
彼得一号
Peter 1!
我拿到了
I got it.
弗林特  我们是在帮你
Flint! We're trying to help you!
兄弟们  我到顶上了
Guys, I'm at the top!
我需要解药
I need the cure!
我来了  我来了  我来了
I'm coming, I'm coming, I'm coming!
博士  我马上回来找你
Doc, I'll be right back.
弗林特  没事了
It's okay, Flint.
我们会把你送回家的
We're gonna get you home.
你只要...待在这儿就好
Just... stay right here.
我们要怎么阻止他  我从没见过他这么强
How do we stop him? I've never seen him this powerful.
是因为弧反应堆  我们得把它取下来
It's the arc reactor. We gotta get it off him.
你们不能拿走这个宝贝
You're not gonna take this away from me.
不管用了噢
That's not gonna work.
好吧  我们必须靠近他
Okay, we've gotta do this up close.
彼得二号去右边  彼得三号去左边  都跟着我
Peter 2 go right, Peter 3 go left. On me.
-你怎么会不知道怎么关上那玩意   -我在试了  没有用啊
-Why don't you know how to close that thing?  -I'm trying to close the gate. It's not working
好吧  我们再试一次  我们只要一直试就行
All right, we're gonna do it again. We're just gonna keep trying.
-好的  我们能行  我能行  可以的   -集中注意力  关上那个传送门
-Alright. We got it. I got it. Got this.   -You try to focus and close the portal.
喔  不 不 不 不
Oh, no. No, no, no!
内德  那个蜥蜴冲过来了  我们应该...
Ned, that is a lizard, and we should...
快跑
Run!
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
康纳斯  住手
Connors, stop!
太棒了
Yeah.
放开他们  他们是我的小蜘蛛
Leave them. They're mine.
我不用你帮忙  我打得正好呢
I don't need your help. I got it just fine.
章鱼博士  不要
Dr. Octavius. No.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
放开我
Get it off me!
这下就对了
There you go.
MJ
MJ!
-我们必须把这个藏起来   -好的  你说的对  对
-We have to hide this thing.   -Okay. Right, right, right.
那个小兔崽子在哪
Where is he?
-等等  等等  等等   -在你动手之前  先生——
-Wait, wait, wait!   -Before you do anything, Mister---
奇异博士  先生  请您听着...
Doctor Strange, sir, well...
彼得的计划奏效了
Peter's plan is working.
-什么计划   -他正在治愈他们
-What plan?   -He's curing them.
康纳斯博士
Dr. Connors?
欢迎回来  先生
Welcome back, sir.
好吧  真想不到啊
Well, I'll be damned.
你刚刚是不是开了个传送门
Did you just open a portal?
是的先生  是我做的
Yes, yes, sir. I did.
麦克斯
Max.
麦克斯...
Max...
别瞎担心了
Don't worry.
-我已经没电了   -你确定吗
-I'm out. Empty.   -You sure about that?
我又变成无名小卒了
I'm back to being a nobody.
-你从来都不是无名小卒  麦克斯   -不  我是的  我就是
-You were never a nobody, Max.   -Yes, I was. Yes, I was.
你之前没见过我
You didn't see me.
我能和你说点事吗
Can I tell you something?
当然
Yeah.
你长得挺清秀的  你还只是个孩子
You got a nice face. You're just a kid.
你来自皇后区...
You're from Queens...
你穿着那件制服...
You got that suit...
你对人们伸出援手...
You helping out people...
我曾以为你会是个黑人
I just thought you was gonna be black.
噢  我不是  很抱歉
Oh, man. I'm sorry.
没关系  别的宇宙一定会存在黑人蜘蛛侠的
Don't mind it. There's gotta be a black Spider-Man somehwere out there.
那必须的
Goddamn yes.
太阳的能量...
The power of the sun...
...就掌握在你的手中
... in the palm of your hand.
彼得
Peter?
奥托
Otto.
能看到你实在是太好了  好孩子
Oh, it's good to see you, dear boy.
是的  见到你实在是太好了
It's good to see you.
你长大了
You're all grown up.
你过得怎么样
How are you?
我争取努力过得更好
Trying to do better.
斯特兰奇  等一下...
Strange, wait...
我在科罗多拉大峡谷上吊了12个小时
I've been dangling over the Grand Canyon for twelve hours!
我知道  我知道  我知道  我...
I know. I know, I know, I know. I...
我真的很抱歉  先生  我是说...
I'm sorry about that, sir. I mean...
你去了科罗多拉大峡谷
You went to the Grand Canyon?
-你本来可以帮他的   -不不不  没关系  没关系
-He could've used your help.   -No, no. It's okay, it's okay.
他们是我的新朋友  这位是彼得·帕克
These are my new friends. This is Peter Parker,
他也是彼得·帕克  蜘蛛侠和蜘蛛侠
he's Peter Parker. Spider-Man, Spider-Man.
他们是平行宇宙的我  他们是来帮忙的
They're mes from other universes. They're here to help.
这是我和你们说过的巫师
This is the wizard that I was telling you about.
听着孩子  我真的很敬佩  你设法给了他们第二次机会
Look, I am really impressed that you managed to give them all a second chance, kid.
但现在这一切都该结束了
But this has to end, now.
蜘蛛侠在家吗  可以出来一起玩吗
Can the Spider-Man come out to play?
斯特兰奇  不要
Strange, no!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
是的  我没事
Yeah. I'm okay.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
谢谢你  斗篷先生
Thank you, Mister Cape, sir.
内德
Ned!
MJ
MJ!
-彼得   -内德
-Peter?   -Ned.
彼得
Peter?
嘿
Hey.
-你们没事吧   -我们没事
-Are you okay?   -We're okay.
可怜的彼得
Poor Peter.
懦弱到不敢送我回去受死
Too weak to send me home to die.
不  我只是想亲手杀了你这个杂种
I just wanna kill you myself.
这就对了  孩子
Attaboy.
她在那
She was there.
因为你...
Because of you...
或许是我扔的炸弹
I may have struck the blow.
但你呢
But you?
你才是害死她的人
You are the one that killed her.
彼得
Peter?
我都做了些什么
What have I done?
-是你啊   -你没事吧
-It's you.   -You okay?
我没事  我之前被捅过几次了
Yeah, I'm good. I've been stabbed before.
-天呐   -嘿
Oh, god. Hey.
天呐
Oh, man.
嘿  接的不错
Hey, nice catch.
你看到了吗
You saw?
那是真的吗  还是我快死了呢
Is that happening? Or am I dying?
喔是  不是你要死了  那是真的
Oh yeah, no. That's happening. That's real.
天上那是有人吗
Are there people in the sky?
-我该走了   -去吧  我来照顾他
-I gotta go.   -Yeah. Yeah, I got him.
你没事吧
Are you ok?
发生什么了
What's happening?
他们快要过来了  我阻止不了他们了
They're starting to come through and I can't stop them.
一定会有办法的  你就不能再施个咒语吗
There's got to be something we can do. Can't you just cast a spell again?
-像我搞砸之前的那样   -太迟了  他们已经到了
-Like the original way. Before I screwed it up.   -We're too late for that. They're here.
他们是因你而来的
They're here because of you.
-如果大家都忘了我的身份呢  -什么
-What if everyone forgot who I was?   -What?
他们是因我而来的  是吧
They're coming here because of me, right?
就因为我是彼得·帕克是吧
Because I'm Peter Parker?
那施个新的咒语吧
So cast a new spell.
但这次  让所有人都忘记彼得·帕克是谁吧
But this time, make everyone forget who Peter Parker is.
让所有人都忘记...
Make everyone forget...
我
Me.
不
No.
但这行得通  是吧
But it would work, right?
是  是行得通
Yeah, it would work.
但你要明白  那意味着所有认识你  爱着你的人
But you got to understand, that would mean everyone, who knows and loves you
我们都会...
We'd...
失去所有关于你的记忆
We'd have no memory of you.
就像你从未存在过一样
It'll be as though you never existed.
我知道
I know.
施咒吧
Do it.
那快去道别吧  你没剩多少时间了
Man, better go and say your goodbyes. You don't have long.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
叫我史蒂芬
Call me Stephen.
谢谢你  史蒂芬
Thank you, Stephen.
对...
Yeah...
感觉还是怪怪的
Still feels weird.
回头见
I'll see you around.
再见了  孩子
So long, kid.
我觉得是时候了  你们该回家了
I think this is it. I think you're about to go home.
-好的   -但我...呃...
-Ok. Alright.   -But I... uhh...
谢谢你们
Thank you.
我只是想...
I just wanted...
我想...我想告诉你们
I want you...I wanna tell you that...
我真的不知道该怎么说
I really don't know how to say this, like...
-彼得   -我想让你们知道我...
-Peter.   -I want you to know that I...
你懂的
You know.
这就是我们的责任
It's what we do.
对  是我们的责任
Yeah. It's what we do.
好了  我得去找内德跟MJ了
Right. I gotta find Ned and MJ.
谢谢  谢谢  谢谢  真的谢谢你们
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you!
我猜我们会再见的
I guess I'll see you.
-再见   -拜拜
-See you.   -Bye.
你很痛  是吧
You're in so much pain, huh?
-对   -是啊
-I am.   -Yeah.
你们还好吗
Are you okay?
嗯  我们没事
Yeah, we're okay.
-噢天啊  你流血了   -没事  我没事
-Oh, my God. You're bleeding.   -No. I'm okay.
-你确定吗   -我真的没事  我保证
-Are you sure?   -I'm fine. I promise.
我们该走了吧  是吧
We should go, right?
你们将会忘记我是谁
You're gonna forget who I am.
什么
What?
忘记你是谁  你在说什么呀
Forget who you are, what are you talking about?
没事的
It's okay...
我会来找你们
I'm gonna come and find you,
然后我会解释一切
and I'll explain everything.
我会让你们记起我
I'll make you remember me.
就像这一切都不曾发生过一样
It'll be like none of this ever happened.
好吗
Okay?
但如果行不通的话怎么办
But what if that doesn't work?
如果行不通的话怎么办  如果我们记不起你该怎么办
What if that doesn't work, what if we can't remember you?
我不想那样
I don't wanna do that.
-我不想那样   -我懂  MJ  我懂
-I don't wanna do that.   -I know. MJ, I know.
一定会有其他办法的
There's gotta be something we can do.
我们能想个计划什么的吗  一定会有其他办法的
We can come up with like a plan or something? You know there's always something we can do.
没有其他办法了
There's nothing we can do.
但我们会没事的
But we'll be okay.
你保证吗
Promise?
对  我保证
Yeah, I promise.
我会来找你们的  好吗
I'll come find you. Okay?
我知道你会来的
I know you will.
你最好来啊
You better.
你要是不来  我还会自己发现你的身份的
If you don't, I'm just gonna figure it out.
毕竟我以前就做到过  我还能再来一回
I've done it before. I can do it again.
我保证我会搞定这一切的
I promise I'll fix this.
我真的恨死魔法了
I really hate magic.
对啊  我也是
Yeah. Me, too.
我爱你
I love you.
-我也爱你   -你发誓
-I love you...   -Swear that,
当我们再次相遇的时候  你会告诉我一切
you will tell me if we meet again.
我发誓
Sure.
自由女神像上的惨案已经过去几个星期了
It's been a few weeks since the fiasco on the Statue of Liberty,
拥护蜘蛛侠的邪教徒们还坚持声称
and Spider-Man's cultists continue to contend
这个罪大恶极的私警是个英雄
that the vile vigilante is a hero.
但他要是个英雄  就该揭下面罩  亮明身份
But if he were a hero, he'd unmask himself and tell us who he really is.
因为只有懦夫才会隐藏身份
Because only a coward conceals his identity.
只有懦夫才会隐瞒心机
Only a coward hides his true intentions.
女士们先生们  你们放心
Rest assured, ladies and gentlemen,
我就算赴汤蹈火
this reporter will uncover those intentions,
也会把他的邪恶目的扒出来
come hell or high water.
你好
Hi.
我是彼得·帕克  你还不认识我  但我...
My name is Peter Parker. You don't know me, but I...
我是彼得·帕克  你还不认识我  但...
My name is Peter Parker and you don't know me, but...
好吧...来吧
Okay... Come on.
你好啊
Hey.
稍等
One sec.
你要点什么
Can I help you?
你好  呃...
Hi. Umm...
我是彼得·帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我...
And I...
想点杯咖啡  谢谢
would like a coffee. Please.
好的  马上好  彼得·帕克
Okay, no problem, Peter Parker.
给我的工程师同学拿个甜甜圈
Donuts for my fellow engineer.
-等等  你说什么   -麻省理工  他们的吉祥物不是工程师吗
-Wait, what?   -MIT, they have the engineers, the mascot.
*注：麻省理工的吉祥物是一只海狸  海狸被誉为"大自然的工程师"
啊对对对  我记下了
Oh, right, right, right. I should probably know that.
看看  你已经很麻省了
Look at you with the school spirit.
随你说吧  我可不认
Tell anybody. I would deny it.
好吧
Oh, okay.
乐意为您效劳
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker?
你的咖啡
Your coffee.
好  谢谢
Right. Thank you.
要去麻省理工了  你激动吗
Are you excited for MIT?
有那么点的
Right. Yeah.
其实我是挺激动的  很怪
Yeah, actually I am excited, which is weird
因为我一般不会因为什么事激动的
because I don't really get excited about things.
我属于那种  提前做好会失望的准备
I kind of expect disappointment.
因为那样的话你就永远不会真的失望
'Cause then you'd never actually be disappointed.
对吧
Right?
确实
Yeah. Right.
怎么说呢  我也说不清...
It's just... I don't know...
这次不知怎么的就不太一样了
It just kinda feels different this time for some reason.
也是
Right.
那真是...
That was...
你没事吧
You okay?
已经不疼了
Doesn't really hurt anymore.
还需要什么吗
Is there anything else?
没了
No.
谢谢
Thank you.
不谢
No problem.
再见了
I'll see you around.
梅·帕克
救一人即救众人
你怎么认识她的
How do you know her?
通过蜘蛛侠
Through Spider-Man.
-你呢   -一样
-You?   -Same.
不久前我一个好朋友过世了
I lost a good friend a while back.
跟现在感觉一模一样
It felt like this.
他们去世就已经让人心痛
Hurts cause they're gone,
接着等你想起他们象征的意义  你又会心痛
and then it hurts all over again because you remember what they stood for,
不禁就会想...
and you wonder...
是不是连那些意义都不在了
Is all that gone too?
不  那些还在
No, it's not gone.
她帮助过的每一个人...
Everybody she helped...
他们会再帮助他人  将精神传递下去
they'll keep it going.
你真这么觉得吗
You really think so?
我很确定
I know it.
保重  好吗
Take care of yourself, okay?
好  很高兴认识你
Yeah. Nice to meet you.
这可是弗兰克这个月第一次
Frank's doing the first of the month.
别迟到了
Don't be late.
好
Okay,
好的  好的  我好像明白了  你是说这个地方...
Okay, okay. I think I got this. You're saying that this whole place here...
遍地都是...
It's just tons of...
超能力人类
Superpeople.
他都说了几个小时了
And he has been saying it for hours.
行  再说一遍  抱歉  我蠢
All right, tell me again. I'm sorry. I'm an idiot.
有那么个亿万富豪  他有铁罐战服
There was a billionaire. He had a tin suit,
他还能飞  是吧
and he could fly. Right?
好的  还有个暴脾气的绿人
Okay. And there was a really angry green man.
-浩克   -浩克
-Hulk.   -Hulk.
就这你还觉得致命守护者这名字很烂
And you thought Lethal Protector was a shit name.
本来就烂嘛
Yeah, because it is.
你再跟我说说那个沉迷石头的紫薯外星人
Now, tell me again about your purple alien that loves stones.
我跟你说啊  兄弟  外星人可不喜欢石头
'Cause I'll tell you what, man. Aliens, they do not love stones.
-埃迪  快给我打住   -不不不  他们才不喜欢石头
-Eddie, don't start!  -No no no, the don't love stones.
你知道外星人喜欢什么吗  吃脑子
You know what aliens love? Eating brains!
他们就好这口  对吧
Because that's what they do. All right?
先生  他可是让我的家人都消失了
Senor, he made my family disappear.
整整五年
For five years.
五年
Five years?
那还挺久的
That's a long time.
也许我应该去趟纽约  跟这个
I mean, maybe I should go to New York and speak to this,
蜘蛛侠聊聊
Spider-Man.
埃迪  我们喝上头了
Eddie! We are drunk!
-咱们裸泳去   -我不要
-Let's go skinny-dip!   -I don't think we should skinny-dip.
先生  你得付酒钱
Sir, you have to pay your bill.
怎么了  不要
What is happening? No!
不要  我们才刚到这里  别又整一回啊
No, we just got here. No, not again.
他就这么走了
And there he goes.
不付钱  不给小费  屁都没有
Without paying the bill, no tips, nothing.
别施那个咒语
Don't cast that spell.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
为什么
Why?
我们破坏了时空的稳定性
We tampered with the stability of spacetime.
多元宇宙...
The Multiverse...
...这个概念  我们知之甚少
...is a concept about which we know frighteningly little.
亵渎现实...
Your desecration of reality...
...必将受到惩罚
...will not go unpunished.
这是唯一的办法
It was the only way.
但现在的局面让我始料未及
But I never meant for any of this to happen.
旺达
Wanda.
我知道你迟早都要现身
Well, I knew sooner or later you'd show up.
我犯了错  伤害了很多人
I made mistakes and people were hurt.
我不是为了西视区的事件来的
I'm not here to talk about Westview.
那你来这里做什么
Then what are you here for?
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
什么事
With what?
你对多元宇宙了解多少
What do you know about the Multiverse?
我很抱歉  史蒂芬
I'm sorry, Stephen.
你要知道
I hope you understand.
对我们的宇宙最大的威胁...
The greatest threat to our universe...
...正是你
...is you.
事态已经开始失控了
Things just got out of hand.
奇 异 博 士 将 会 回 归